馬庫斯·胡克斯和正拳組和帶來第6張專輯
Marcus Hooks and the Real Deal, take 6.
-應該報三個人的名字  -你要我來唱主旋律嗎
- That's three names. - You want me to sing the main line?
好啦  開唱吧  開唱吧
Oh, yeah, here we go, here we go.
今晚我們將踏上南下的音樂之旅
Tonight we take a musical journey south,
傳奇靈魂樂樂隊馬庫斯·胡克斯和正拳組合
where the legendary soul band Marcus Hooks and the Real Deal
就是在那裡練就了他們的標誌性嗓音
developed their signature sound.
1  2
1, 2!
開始的時候  3人只是
They started out singing for pennies
在孟菲斯的市井賣唱
On the street corners of Memphis.
片名  靈魂歌手
拉拉繩
Pull the string
我就向你眨眨眼
And I'll wink at you
我是你的玩偶
I'm your puppet
我會逗你笑
I'll do funny things
如果你想要
If you want me to
我是你的玩偶
I'm your puppet
我是你的
I'm yours
永遠被你操縱
To have and to hold
親愛的  你能全權操控我這個小木偶
Darling, you've got full control of your puppet
但到了1972年
But by 1972,
馬庫斯·胡克斯和正拳組合
Marcus Hooks and the Real Deal
已經成為藍調音樂界的領軍樂隊
had become one of the biggest R&B acts in the world.
只有甜蜜靈魂樂
Nothin' like sweet soul music
讓我們同聚首
To bring us together
他們在全球的演唱會票房都很火爆
They played to sellout houses all over the world.
賣出600萬張唱片
They'd sold 6 million records
同時他們影響了一代美國樂壇
and influenced a generation of American musicians.
伴著甜蜜靈魂樂翩翩起舞
Dance to the sweet soul music
但這一切在1977年7月24日終結
But that all ended on July 24, 1977,
因為馬庫斯·胡克斯在紐約麥迪遜花園
when Marcus Hooks began his solo career
舉辦了一場激動人心的演唱會
with a dramatic concert
宣告自己單飛
at New York's Madison Square Garden.
女士們   先生們
Ladies and gentlemen,
歡迎馬庫思·胡克斯
Marcus Hooks.
正當胡克斯在樂壇叱吒風雲之時
But while Hooks became a music legend,
樂隊的另兩個成員弗洛伊德·亨德森和
the journey took a decidedly different direction
路易斯·海因茲毅然改變了曲風
for former band mates Floyd Henderson and Louis Hinds.
他們憑藉《公園漫步》一曲成名
Renowned for their signature dance stylings
其獨特的舞步風格讓他們備受讚譽
from their one breakout hit, "Walk in the Park,"
但是二人於1979年分道揚鑣
the duo broke up in 1979.
據說是因為創作意見分歧
Citing creative differences
並且各自奔向自己的前程
and a desire to pursue separate projects.
退後  不許動
Back off! Freeze!
舉起手  讓我看見你的手
Get your hands up! Let me see them!
等等  等等  這不是...
Oh. Wait. Wait, wait. It ain't... Ohh!
槍是假的  不是真槍
The gun ain't real! Ow! It ain't real! Ow!
最新消息  正拳樂隊成員路易斯·海因茲被捕
我只是沒錢了  見鬼
I'm just broke, God it!
我沒想傷害誰
I ain't tryin' to hurt no!
小心你的爪子
Watch your damn hands!
警察真他媽的殘忍
Police mother brutality!
而另一位弗洛伊德·亨德森
While Floyd Henderson...
歡迎光臨弗洛伊德洗車服務公司
Come on down to Floyd's Car Wash,
您的愛車全部享受手工擦洗服務
where everything is done by hand.
他將其出色的表演
...combined his showmanship
同商業頭腦相結合
with an entrepreneur spirit.
別忘了"銷魂星期日"哦
And don't forget about Super Soul Sundays,
整車清洗
with a full body wash
外帶免費清洗輪胎
to guarantee a free rimjob.
來吧  免費洗輪胎
Come on. Get your rimjob.
快來免費洗輪胎
Come get your rimjob.
Come and get your rimjob!
被人遺忘的正拳組合亨德森和
Whatever happened to the forgotten duo Henderson and Hinds
海因茲究竟都遭遇了什麼呢
The Real Deal?
寶貝  把導航儀打開
Baby, turn the navigation on.
希望在天黑前能到地方
I hope we can find this place sometime tonight.
他會愛上那兒的
He gonna love it there.
那裡有坎麥可調床
They got Craftmatic adjustable beds,
聲控燈
clap-on lamps.
跟你們說過了  最好安靜點
Y'all better shut up back there, I'm tellin' you.
我真想把手伸到後座上
I'm gonna reach back there
把一個小崽子倒拎起來揍一頓
and pop one of them little boys upside the head so bad.
弗洛伊德叔叔  我想這就是我們要的
I think that's it, Uncle Floyd.
真不敢相信我竟然任你埋怨
Now, I can't believe I let you talk me into this bullshit.
你想說什麼  這多美啊  你不喜歡嗎
What you talking about? It's beautiful. You don't like this?
這就是一死氣沉沉的營地
It's a death camp.
叔叔  它怎麼就是死氣沉沉的營地啦
Oh, how is it a death camp, Unc?
這裡有36個洞高爾夫場地
We got 36 holes of golf.
3個游泳池
Three swimming pools.
這地方的男女比例
You know the ratio of women to men here
是1比5  叔叔  1比5啊
is 5 to 1, Unc? 5 to 1.
意思是這的小妞兒一大片
That mean you got 'em everywhere.
擠得你都動不了  到處是小妞兒...
You can't even move. There's women...
隨便看一圈
Every time you look around,
身邊到處都是妞兒
women crawling between your legs, arms, anything.
見鬼  叔叔  如果你擔心生意的話
I mean, damn, Unc. And if you're worried about the business,
我來搞定
I got that.
你那套我都學會了
You taught me everything you know.
是啊
Yeah.
行啊  我告訴你  小子
Yeah. You know something, son?
你真夠狡猾的
You're real crafty.
多謝誇獎
Appreciate that.
第一步  你搬進我家
See, first you move into my house.
然後  你搶走我的生意
Then you take over my business.
-夥計  我沒有搶走  -對了  還有
- Aw, man, I ain't taking...  - Oh, yeah.
夥計  再然後  你想盡辦法騙我到這個山谷來
Then you move me all the way out to the Valley, man,
就沒人聽到我尖叫了  對不
so can't nobody hear me scream. Right?
實際上  這就是為啥把你弄到這來
Actually, that's why we're moving you here.
在這裡護士才能聽見你的驢叫
So the nurses can hear your ass scream.
還記得你摔倒在地板上躺了三天嗎
You remember you fell on that floor for three days
-沒人聽見你求救  -我記得
- and couldn't nobody hear you. - I remember.
那就行了  別抱怨啦  享受人生吧  叔叔
Yeah. Now, stop being bitter, man. Enjoy yourself, Unc.
你的黃金時代到來了  夥計
There are your golden years, player.
來吧  進屋裡來
Now, come on in the house and say bye
和沙琳還有孩子們告別
to Charlene and the kids.
見鬼的小崽子
Fuck them kids.
Fuck the kids?
就是
Yeah.
就這樣  寶貝兒
Ohhh... yeah, baby.
快給我  快  快點
Ohh! Oh, give it to me. Give it to me nice and hard.
就是這樣
Oh, right there!
寶貝  別停
Ooh. Don't stop, baby.
不  你不能跑
No, you're not getting away.
真爽
Yummy!
髖關節感覺怎樣
How's the hip?
還行
Fine.
那就好
Okay.
好了  亨德森先生
Okay, Mr. Henderson.
請站起來  面向窗戶
I'm gonna need you to, uh, stands up, face the window,
趴在桌子上
and bend over the table.
大夫  我的病跟屁股沒關係
My problem ain't back in that area, doctor.
亨德森先生  你的睡眠問題
Look, Mr. Henderson, your sleep problem
可能是多種原因引起的
can be a symptom of a myriad of different conditions,
其中之一  就是
some of which, you know, are...
您的屁股
well, you know, back in that area.
我討厭有人像同性性交那樣在我後面
I don't like nobody behind me like that, Huds.
告訴你  我不喜歡有人捅我的
I'm telling you, I just don't like nobody playing
-屁股眼  -我會很輕很輕的
- with my penny. - I'll be very gentle.
您不會有多大感覺的
I'll be in and out before you know it.
趴那兒  對了
Just bend over. There you go.
抓住  抓緊啦
Hold on, now. Get a good grip.
放鬆
Just relax.
Relax.
坐在海邊碼頭上
Sittin' on the dock of the bay
看海...潮
Watching the tiiiiiide
潮...起...潮...落
Roll away
好了  亨德森先生  再說一次
All right, again, Mr. Henderson,
您身體絕對沒問題
there's absolutely nothing wrong with you.
吃點治療失眠的藥就行
So take those for insomnia.
再有問題給我打電話  好嗎
Give me a call if anything changes. All right?
-好的  -幫幫忙
- All right.  - Do me a favor.
別太勉強自己了  亨德森先生
Stop being so hard on yourself, Mr. Henderson.
退休是一種痛苦的人生轉變
Retirement can be a tough transition.
對不
All right?
好啦  對了  記住
Okay. Oh, yeah. Hey, listen.
不要用酒喂藥
Don't mix those sleeping pills with alcohol
除非你想自殺
unless you want to kill yourself.
行了  下一個
Okay. Who's next?
南部地區
And for those of you in the Southland,
明天是陽光明媚
tomorrow's gonna be another beautiful day with
的美好一日
bright, sunny skies
溫度在85華氏度左右
and temperatures into the mid-80s.
打高爾夫球的好天氣
A perfect day for some golf.
並且晴朗天氣將一直持續到下周
And that's gonna continue right into next week.
晴空暖陽
Gorgeous blue skies and sensationally warm.
再愜意不過了
It doesn't get any better than that.
插播新聞
This just in.
全球的靈魂樂迷聚集起來
Soul music fans around the globe
悼念馬庫斯·胡克斯
are mourning the loss of Marcus Hooks.
這位傳奇的歌手兼曲作者
The legendary singer and songwriter
因心臟病突發去世
apparently suffered a massive heart attack
病發時正在座無虛席的瑞典斯德哥爾摩
while performing last night in front of a capacity crowd
昆斯坦丁體育場做告別演唱
at Kungstrardgarden Park in Stockholm, Sweden.
他的遺體將運回紐約家中
His body's being flown home to New York,
下周將舉行告別儀式
where a memorial service will be held next week.
這位7屆格萊美獎的獲得者
The seven-time Grammy Award winner
享年63歲
was 63 years old.
我願為你做任何事情
I'll do anything for you
稍後請繼續收看
We're back in just a moment.
克在因修車廠  什麼事
Kezian Motors. Can I help you?
找誰
Who?
海因茲  你的電話
Hinds, telephone!
你小子是不在外面搞毒品買賣
Dealing drugs out of my garage?
聽著  你要是敢幹犯法的事
Listen, you doing something illegal,
讓我發現了  就把你踢回監獄去
I'll find out and send your ass back to prison
所以他媽的快點講電話
so fucking fast,
這會讓你滿是銅臭的黑腦袋瓜暈掉
it will make your black monkey head spin.
要是以前  你這樣和我說胡話
You know, there was a time
我就敲碎你的牙
I would've knocked your teeth down your throat
讓你嚥下去
for saying some shit like that to me.
但是現在我改過自新了
But I'm a changed man.
一心一意做現在這些爛事
I'm trying to be all centered and shit.
我可以把你叫作
Now, I could called you
長著一條眉毛混飯吃的大屁股雜種
a unibrow-shaving, pilaf-eating, greasy-ass goat fucker,
但我沒那麼說  是吧
But I didn't, did I?
因為我不想傷你的感情
'Cause I didn't want to hurt your feelings,
也不想惹你生氣
and I didn't want to piss you off,
正如我內心深處非常明白
just like I know deep, deep down inside,
你也不想惹我生氣
you don't want to piss me off, either.
你說呢
Now, do you?
是的
Uh-uh. No. Uh-uh.
好啦
All right.
我們和好
Peace.
是  我是路易斯
Yeah, this is Louis.
您好  海因茲先生
Hey. Mr. Hinds.
我是丹尼·愛普斯坦  我在紐約  您還好嗎
It's Danny Epstein calling from New York. How are you today?
你是
Who?
馬蒂的兒子
Marty's son.
是嗎
Oh, yeah?
靠
Shit,
我上次見你  你還戴尿布呢
I ain't seen you since you were in diapers.
是啊
Yeah. Well,
我想您已經聽說
I assume you heard
馬庫斯去世了吧
about Marcus' passing, yeah?
恩  我在心裡默默流淚來的
Oh, yeah. I'm crying the tears of a motherfucking clown.
好了  事情是這樣
Okay. Here's the thing.
VH1台想在阿波羅舉辦一場告別演出
VH1 is putting together a farewell tribute at the Apollo,
並列了一份重要人物的出場名單
and they got a lot of big names lined up.
他們想讓亨德森和海因茲表演  是嗎
And they want Henderson and Hinds to perform, right?
正確  正拳組合再聚首
That's right! The Real Deal back together again.
是個大好機會
It's a great opportunity.
你和弗洛伊德說了嗎
You talk to Floyd?
說了
I did.
亨德森先生同意參加
Mr. Henderson is in.
很好
Good.
可我不參加
Then I'm out.
始於壞時跡
Born under a bad sign
我從井底向上爬
Been down since I began to crawl
實在不是運氣壞
If it wasn't for bad luck
我就從來不走運阿
You know I wouldn't have no luck at all
命運多坎坷...
Hard luck and trouble...
真噁心
That is disgusting.
難以置信
I don't believe this. Hmm.
見鬼
Ohh. Damn!
夥計  你他媽的幹什麼
Ooh. Fuck happened, man?
鬼才知道  我進來  看見你在那兒
Hell if I know. I came in, found your ass laying there.
胡說  你直勾勾地盯著我
Bullshit. You looked me dead in my eyes.
夥計  你早就認出我了
Man, you recognized me.
我沒認出來  你變了好多
I didn't recognize you. You done changed.
我一路趕來
I come all the way down here,
可老兄你就瞅我一眼
and, man, you gonna look me in my face
-給我一拳  -你該事先打電話的
- and knock me the fuck out? - Should've called first.
我咋打電話
How the hell I'm gonna call
你都沒電話
and you ain't got no phone?
啥樣的人沒有電話
What kind of person ain't got no land phone?
不想接電話的人
Kind of person don't want to get no calls.
你甚至都不問問
You don't even know why I came down
我來這破地方幹啥
to this old fucked-up-the-ass neighborhood.
我知道你來幹啥  小愛普跟我說了
I talked to little Ep. I know why you're here.
我的回答是不
And the answer is no.
他說了演出是在阿波羅並且票都賣光了嗎
Did he tell you we're at the Apollo and they sold out?
跟你說其他的出場的名人了嗎
Did he also tell you who gonna be there?
布克·T·瓊斯  艾薩克·海耶斯  布特西·柯林斯
Booker T. Jones. Isaac Hayes. Bootsy Collins.
還有莎奇拉
Shakira.
關我屁事
I don't care.
就算為馬庫斯
Do it for Marcus.
去他媽的馬庫斯
Fuck Marcus.
好吧  那就為了我
Well, do it for me.
-去你媽的  -別這樣  夥計
- Fuck you!  - Come on, man.
-這是我們的機會  -啥機會
- This is our shot.  - At what?
復出啊  傻瓜  我們做好了的話
At a comeback, fool. If we do this shit right,
就能拿到唱片合約  再征歌壇
we can get a record deal and get back on the road
像30年前的那樣
like we was 30 years ago.
我可不想像30年前那樣
I ain't trying to be like 30 years ago!
我也不想復出
I ain't trying to make no comeback.
我離開了  就不想回去
I'm gone, and I want to stay gone.
夥計  你想讓我求你嗎
Don't make me beg you, man.
老子曰  "故常無慾以觀其妙"
Lao-Tzu says, "Free from desire, you realize the mystery."
"常有欲以觀其徼"
"Caught in desire, you see only the manifestations. "
這他媽的啥意思  夥計
What the fuck that even mean, man?
意思就是
That means...
你他媽的給我滾出去
get the fuck out.
我猜你沒想到可以賺到錢吧
Well, I guess you don't give a fuck about the money, huh?
賺什麼錢  那是個葬禮
What money? It's a funeral!
葬禮上唱歌是沒錢賺的
Nobody get paid to sing at no damn funeral!
能賺多少
How much?
4萬塊
40 grand.
每個人嗎
A piece?
不  兩人分
No, down the middle.
不不不  不不不
No, no, no, no, no, No, no, no, no!
那沒多少
That ain't even enough.
夥計  沒多少是什麼意思
What the fuck you mean that's not enough, man?
我還是喜歡這裡的生活方式
I got a lifestyle to maintain here.
夥計  這是什麼生活方式
What kind of lifestyle, man,
你腰纏萬貫嗎
you filthy motherfucker?
滿櫃子都是狗糧  可我沒看見狗
You got a pantry full of dog food. I don't see no dog.
狗在床底下  黑鬼
Dog under the bed, nigger! You lucky
你進門  狗沒咬你屁股算你走運
he ain't attacked your ass when you came in.
你就是那條狗  混蛋
You're the dog, motherfucker!
你的存款都幹什麼用了  夥計
What happened to all that fucking money you done saved, man?
存款  放屁
Saved? Shit.
從水門事件那時開始直到
I don't remember shit from Watergate
航天飛機爆炸
to when the space shuttle blew up.
我就不記得有存款
Hmm. Money I saved.
好吧  還有歌曲的版稅呢
Okay, what about the royalties?
我曾經每年能得到3萬塊呢
I used to get over $30,000 a year off that shit.
我賭撲克輸了我的那份  行了吧
I lost my royalties in a poker game. All right?
-撲克  -你聽好  夥計
- Poker? - Listen here, man.
如果你真想讓我
If you serious about un-assing me
再度出山
from my lavish surroundings here,
夥計  你得考慮
man, you gonna have to be a little more flexible
小讓一步  就...
in your thinking. Say, oh...
我6你4吧
60/40.
夥計  你可真是混帳加三級
Man, you must be higher than a motherfucker.
我們一直對半分的
We always split shit straight down the middle.
如果我不去演出
Ain't gonna be nothing to split
你連分都沒啥可分的  是吧
if I don't show up, now, is there?
分不到6成  我就不去
And I ain't showing up unless I get 60% of the proceeds.
反正你有錢  混帳東西
You rich anyway, motherfucker.
我在電視上看過的你洗車廣告了
I seen your little car wash commercials on the TV.
我已經把所有的生意都轉給我外甥了
I transferred all my business affairs over to my nephew.
-我現在靠固定收入  夥計  -那又怎樣
- I'm on a fixed income, man. - So what?
那就是中大獎了
So your draws!
所以現在2萬元對我來說
That's why that 20 damn thousand dollars
-很有吸引力  -是一萬六
- look good to me right now.- 16!
六四分成後你該得的那份
That's your cut of a 60/40 split.
這就是我的條件
And those are my terms.
而且沒有商量的餘地
And they're non-negotiable.
55/45
55/45.
去你大爺的
Fatherfuck you, man.
你要我六四分
You're gonna tell me 60/40.
你有什麼資格命令我
You don't dictate to me!
我是他媽的弗洛伊德·亨德森
I'm Floyd motherfucking Henderson.
你和馬庫斯  都是我
You and Marc, I made you
造就了你和那個混蛋
and that motherfucker!
你不會唱歌  不會發鼻音  不會他媽的跳音
You can't sing, hum,or motherfucking skip.
我說得不對嗎
Ain't that a bitch?
都他媽的見鬼去吧
Skip on these motherfucking nuts!
希望你和馬庫斯都下地獄
You and Marcus, may you rest in shit.
混蛋  我是弗洛伊德·亨德森
Motherfucker.I'm Floyd fucking Henderson,
你這個道貌岸然的混蛋
you Apostle-faced motherfucker!
這個混蛋又沖我摔門
This motherfucker slams this door in my face one more time...
我煩透這個混蛋了
I'm tired of this motherfucker!
總是和這個混蛋過不去
Always had a problem with this bitch.
他啥都不是  一無所知
He ain't nothing. He's ignorant!
一個混蛋白痴
Motherfucker's just a idiot.
頭腦簡單的混球  整天無所事事
Chihuahua-head motherfucker, man, sitting up there,
還告訴別人自己有多忙
always want to tell somebody what to damn do.
他難道都是和傻子吹牛
He gonna sit there and talk the fool?
娘的  我血壓又升高了
Ooh, my blood pressure's high, motherfucker.
不要讓這個混蛋氣成這樣
Don't let this motherfucker get you like this.
又怎麼啦
What!
別叫
Stay!
首先  我要明確聲明並記錄在案
First of all, I clearly want to state this for the record.
我發現這種分配方式太卑鄙了  夥計
And I find this arrangement we got,man, despicable.
但我是弗洛伊德·亨德森  一個老演員
But I'm Floyd Henderson.I'm a trouper.
你知道我會不惜一切代價
And you know I'd do any doggone thing, man,
讓這個樂隊重返樂壇  夥計
to see this group get back on its feet,
因為你知道我是就是那種人
'cause you know that's the type of motherfucker I am.
但是  同時
But in the meantime,
我要回我一晚上600美元的賓館了
'm going back to my $600-a-night hotel room,
去洗個舒服的泡泡浴
and I'm gonna have me a nice hot bubble bath
洗掉這一身從你住的黑屋裡
to wash some of this filth and dirt and grime
染上的污垢和晦氣
from this black fucking hole you live in.
然後再吃上一頓肥美多汁
Then I'm having me a nice, juicy-ass steak, oh, yeah,
和你屁股一樣大的牛排
the size of your motherfucking back.
再然後沖個澡刮刮鬍鬚
Then I'm gonna take me a shit shower and shave.
早上六點鐘我會到這裡
And I'll be here at 6 a. m.
接你去該死的機場
To take you to the motherfucking airport.
-聽清楚了  -我不坐飛機
- You got me? - I don't fly.
且我早上8點起床
And I get up at 8.
等我表弟從州監獄出來
My cousin out the penitentiary,
我就讓他宰了這混蛋
I'm gonna have him kill this motherfucker!
他媽的跟我說話沒大沒小
Man talk to me like I'm a motherfucking kid.
我可不是三歲小孩
I ain't no motherfucking kid.
每次我們一起上路
Every time we... we start on the road,
他就開始說同樣的廢話
he starts in saying the same shit.
喂  誰給我拿午飯
Hey! Who's got my lunch?
你是誰
Who are you?
先生  我是菲利浦·紐曼
I'm Phillip Newman, sir,
新來的實習生  你大約
the new intern. You hired me,
20分鐘前雇了我
like, 20 minutes ago.
查克斯·紐曼是我叔叔
Chuckles Newman's my uncle.
-是他告訴你...  -住嘴
- He's the one that told you...- Stop talking.
-遵命  -我已經給了你一份工作
- Very good. - I already got a job for you.
好嗎  看看那個
Okay? Bing, bang, boom.Look at that.
對  亨德斯和海因茲  馬庫斯以前的和聲
Yeah. Henderson and Hinds,Marcus' old backup singers,
對悼念什麼的一無所知
are being real dickheads about this tribute thing...
天啊  亨德森和海因茲  正拳組合
Oh, my God! Henderson and Hinds!The Real Deal.
他們是唯一一支在單集《靈魂列車》中
They're the only band that got to play three songs
演唱三首插曲的樂隊
on a sing episode of Soul Train.
唐·科尼利厄斯當時在場  我還錄下來了
Don Cornelius was there as a witness,and I got it on VHS.
他們來這兒不是干這個  好嗎
They don't do that here. All right?
-是的  先生  -這是唱片公司
- Yes, sir.  - This is a record label,
不是歌迷俱樂部
not a fan club.
我要那兩個老傢伙週六到這裡
I want those two old fucks there on Saturday,
現在派你去辦這件事
and I want you to make that happen.
明白了嗎
Got it?
正拳組合要復出  誰也無法阻擋
The Real Deal is back,and they not gonna stop us now.
該死的
Ohh! Shit.
那他媽的是什麼  夥計
What the fuck is that, man?
槍啊
This is a gun.
沒它就無法穿過三K黨的地盤
I never travel through Klan country without one.
-你介意嗎  -當然
- You got a problem with that, pops?  - Yeah,
我對那很有意見  夥計
I got a problem with that, man.
上次我看到槍的時候
The last time I saw that gun,
你正指著我  要打我
you were pointing at me,and you were shooting it.
聽好了  弗洛伊德  我們不是兩個老朋友
Listen here, Floyd.We ain't two old friends
在某個週日駕車去做什麼
out for some Sunday drive
緬懷往事的旅遊  懂嗎
down Memory Lane. All right?
事實上  我一看見你就來氣
Fact is, I can hardly stand the sight of your ass,
所以你就不要惹我
so you best not to provoke me.
惹了又怎樣
Or what's gonna happen?
從這裡到我們目的地之間
There's a lot of empty road
有很多空蕩蕩的路
between here and where we trying to go.
在那裡如果一個黑鬼消失了
Where a nigger could disappear
也不會有人想他
and where nobody'd miss his black ass.
讓我看看那支槍
Well, let me see that gun.
讓我看看
Let me see it!
小心點啊  傻瓜
Be careful, fool.
你以為我不會拿槍嗎  夥計
You don't think I know how to hold a gun, man?
我可是美國步槍射擊運動協會的一員
I'm a member of the NRA, man.
在哪...怎麼...老天啊
Where's... Now, what's... God damn it!
該死
Oh! Shit!
見鬼
Damn it.
開走  開走  該死的  開走
Drive! Drive! God damn it, drive!
救命
Help me!
抓住方向盤  蠢貨
Grab the wheel, fool!
-小心  -現在拐彎  拐啊
- Look out!  - Now, turn! Turn!
你他媽的什麼毛病
What the hell is wrong with you!
不要在車裡開槍
Don't shoot no gun in a car!
你說...保險栓沒拉上嗎
You said... The safety wasn't on there.
保險栓個屁
Safety, my ass!
保險栓沒有
Safety wasn't...
NRA
NRA!
黑人遲鈍協會
Negro Retards' Association!
真他媽的蠢貨
Dumb motherfucker.
亞利桑那州  旗杆鎮
距阿波羅演出還有4天
僅此一晚  千載難逢  正拳組合
那是什麼鬼東西
What the fuck is that?
致  意
R-E-S-P-E-C-T.
好久沒有在霓虹燈上看到我們的名字了
Been a long time since we saw our name in lights.
我們的名字怎麼在霓虹燈上
What our name doing up in lights?
我們週末要在阿波羅劇場演出
We're at the Apollo Theater this weekend.
我們有30多年沒上過舞台了
We ain't been on stage in over 30 years.
現在  最不應該做的事情
Now, the last thing you want to do
就是在這裡傻站著  是不是
is stink up the joint. Am I right?
所以我準備了一些熱身演唱
And I got us free dinner to boot.
夥計  我還留著這些衣服真是走運
Man, we sure are lucky I kept these threads.
看我們多帥啊
Do we look good!
希望那紐扣不會迸出去傷到人
Better hope that button don't pop off and kill nobody.
天啊  褲子這麼緊希望不會擠爆我的蛋蛋
God damn, I wish these pants weren't squeezing my nuts so tight.
也許會幫你唱出高音
Maybe it'll help you hit those high notes.
我根本不需要幫助就能唱出高音
I don't need help hitting the high notes.
-是啊  走著瞧  -走著瞧
- Yeah, right. We'll see. - We'll see.
哈哈  撐爆了
Ha ha! Busting out.
女士們  先生們
Ladies and gentlemen,
今晚旗杆鎮汽車旅館
tonight, the Flagstaff Motor Inn
隆重推薦30年來
is proud to present to you back onstage
首次重返舞台
for the first time in nearly three decades
唱出令人難忘的悅耳靈魂之聲的
the unforgettable sweet soul sounds of...
正拳組合
The Real Deal!
是不是每次
Don't you ever
傷心
Be sad
偎在我身邊
Lean on me
度過艱難時光
When times are bad
當那時來臨
When the day comes
而你沉沒在
And you are down
煩惱之河
In a river of trouble
好像就要窒息
And are about to drown
只需堅持
Just hold on
我來了
I'm coming
堅持住
Hold on
我來了
I'm coming
馬上就到
On my way
親愛的
Your lover
如果你冷
When you be cold
我為你擋風
I'll be your cover
不必擔心
Don't have to worry
我在這裡
'Cause I'm here
無需召喚
No need to summon me there
我在這裡
'Cause I'm here
堅持住
Hold on
我來了
I'm coming
只需堅持
Just hold on
我來了
I'm coming
只需堅持
Just hold on
我來了
I'm coming
聽我說  召喚我
Look here. Reach out to me
來得到滿足
for some satisfaction.
你知道  弗洛伊德  她要做的
You know, Floyd, all she got to do
是召喚我
Is call my name
來得到回應
For quick reaction
路  路  你沒事吧  沒事吧
Lou, Lou, you all right? You all right?
我喘不上氣來了
I can't breathe!
路易斯
Louis.
繼續唱  繼續唱
Keep going. Keep going.
我喘不上氣來
I can't breathe.
女士們  先生們  請原諒我們
Ladies and gentlemen,please forgive us
這個技術性失誤
for this technical difficulty.
我的眼睛  夥計
Fucking eye, man!
對不起  夥計  褲子太緊了
I'm sorry, man. I got on these tight slacks!
我會起訴你這個胖豬的
Well, then, I'll sue your fat ass!
你起訴個鳥啊
You sue these nuts.
-去啊  滾吧  -上帝啊
- Go on, get on outta here. - Jesus!
我們從頭開始
Take it from the top.
我們怎麼從頭開始啊
How are we gonna take it from the top?
-我可以從頭唱了  夥計  -你連呼吸都困難
- I'm rewed up to go, man,- You can't hardly breathe.
-你可能需要做個胸透  -我沒事
- You may need a chest X-ray.  - I'm good!
在座的有醫生嗎
Is there a doctor in the house?
我愛你  黛比
I love you, Debbie.
滾遠點  蠢貨
Get off me, Ernest T!
路  路  路  冷靜  夥計
Lou. Lou. Lou. Calm down, man.
不用等到12點再離開了  夥計
Ain't but 12 motherfuckers out here, man.
這兒還有觀眾
It's still a audience!
就算只有兩三個仍然是觀眾
I don't care if it's two or three.It's a audience.
這就是我說的
That's what I'm talking about.
你的態度壞了事
Your attitude is fd up.
以前也是這樣搞砸的
Same thing that messed us up back in the day.
不是  你知道我們怎麼搞砸的嗎
No. You know what fucked our shit up back in the day?
不  我不知道
No. I don't know.
你他媽當然知道
Oh, you know goddamn well
我們以前到底怎麼搞砸的
what fucked our shit up back in the day.
-我知道嗎  -是的  你當然知道
- Oh, I do, huh?  - Yes, you do!
我們過去搞砸了
What fucked our shit up back in the day
是因為你搞了我的女人
was you sticking your johnson in my woman!
女士們  先生們
Ladies and gentlemen,
我是弗洛伊德·亨德森
I'm Floyd Henderson.
這個白痴是路易斯·海因茲
This fool is Louis Hinds.
我們是正拳組合  是真的
We are The Real Deal,and that's for real.
感謝你們今晚大駕光臨
I want to thank you for being a super audience here tonight.
混蛋
Motherfucker.
對不起傷到你了  黛比  回來吧
I'm sorry I hit you, Debbie. Come back.
你他媽的閉嘴  不然我就敲暈你
Shut the fuck up,or I'll knock your dick in the dirt.
該死的醉鬼
Drunk son of a bitch.
開心
Happy
路易斯  我們是談談昨晚的事
Hey, Louis, are we gonna talk about last night,
還是繼續慪氣
or we just gonna let it fester?
好吧  我是有點遲鈍  行了吧
All right. Well, I was a little rusty, okay?
說你遲鈍都是輕的
That's a insult to rust, ain't it?
那你呢  混蛋
Well, what about you, motherfucker?
昨晚上你好像被水泥卡住了似的
Last night, look like you were stuck in cement.
路易斯  我做過髖關節置換手術
I had a hip replacement, Louis.
那你應多付100美元
Well, you should've paid a hundred more dollars
換一個豪華點  有點節奏感的型號
and got the deluxe model with some rhythm in it.
就因為你換的那個破髖關節
'Cause that motherfucker you got,
-它不好使  -算你對  夥計
- it ain't working.- Oh, that's fine, man.
但是我們要談的不是這個
But that's not what we talking about.
我是說奧黛特
I'm talking about Odetta.
路易斯  如果我們之間
Louis, if I thought there was still
-仍然有問題...  -你幹了
- gonna be a problem between us...- You went
不該干的事情
where you shouldn't have gone,
就是這麼回事
period!
現在  這爛事還
Now, there's some shit
余臭未消
that's just etched in stone.
最重要的是
First and foremost is
朋友妻  不可欺
thou shall not dig for diamonds in another brother's mine!
胡扯  夥計  你自己也有責任
Bullshit, man. You gotta take some responsibility here.
你以為她不知道
You think she didn't know, man,
你吸菸
about all of your smoking
酗酒  和吸毒
and drinking and drugs
還有睡別的女人  她知道
and other women? She knew.
她跑過來告訴我  "我的男人
She came running to me telling, "My man
路易斯做這  路易斯做那  抱抱我  弗洛伊德"
Louis did this. Louis did that.Hold me, Floyd. "
那好  睡了她不打緊
All right, well, getting the pussy is one thing.
-你也不必和她結婚吧  -什麼
- You ain't had to marry her.- What?
你就是個只會脫褲子的蠢貨
You'd have to be a zip-down fool
讓她從你手指尖溜走了  夥計
to let her slide through your fingers, man.
好吧  如果我是蠢貨  你也是
All right, well, if I'm a fool, then you are, too.
你以為我不知道  她也傷了我的心
You think I don't know that? She hurt my heart, too.
很好  這真是他媽的少得可憐的安慰
Good!That's a poor motherfucking comfort.
但是  不管怎麼說  也是個安慰
But it's comfort, nonetheless.
每晚我都告訴你
Every night I'm telling
只要在這裡  你就會快樂
Every time you're here, you're making
那你在奧黛特之後又結過幾次婚
Well, how many times did you say you was married after Odetta?
四次
Four.
我和一個叫埃斯特爾的女孩兒結婚
I married this girl named Estelle
想忘掉奧黛特
to get over Odetta.
後來又和亨麗埃塔結婚
Then I married Henrietta.
她不適合我
She wasn't no good for me.
後來又和喬瑟芬結婚
Then I married Josephine.
她當然也不適合我  因為後來她遇見了卡爾
She definitely wasn't no good for me because she met Carl.
好  那是第三個
All right. That's three.
誰是幸運的第四個呢
Who was lucky number four?
她叫康斯薇洛
Her name was Consuelo.
她離開我回古巴了
She left me and went back to Cuba.
哈哈  人們還真願意回古巴
Ha ha ha!People actually go back to Cuba?
她說她寧願餘生待在
She said she'd rather spend the rest of her life
獨裁國家也不願意再跟我多待一個晚上
under that dictatorship than spend another night with me.
你呢  你為什麼不結婚
How 'bout you? How come you never got married?
我本來可以在菲律賓的馬尼拉
I almost hooked up with this girl down in the Philippines,
搭上一女孩兒的
in Manila.
但是  我不會說
But, uh, I couldn't learn to speak
塔加路族語  她唯一會的英語就是
Tagalog, and only English she knew
花兩美元我就讓你爽個夠
was, "Me love you long time for two dollar. "
在奧黛特之後我就不擅長談戀愛
Yeah, I wasn't no good at relationships after Odetta.
你有她的消息嗎
You ever hear from her?
誰  那個菲律賓女孩兒
Who, Mai Mai?
不是  奧黛特
No. Odetta.
沒有  夥計
Oh. No, man.
我有過她的消息  夥計
I heard from her, man.
就在聖誕節的時候
It was sometime around Christmas.
她住在塔爾薩  你知道嗎
You know, in that place she was living in Tulsa. You know?
媽的  啪  啪  啪  啪  啪
Fuck it.Pow, pow, pow, pow, pow.
你在幹什麼
What you doing?
-我看到一個歹徒  -你為什麼不把槍口朝上
- I saw a coyote. - Whyn't you put that thing up
省得傷到人  夥計
before somebody get hurt, man?
你怎麼老覺得我不會拿
How come you think I don't know how to handle
-這玩意  夥計  -認為
- no damn piece, man? - Think?
是知道
I know.
是嗎
Yeah?
好吧  過來和我練練  路易斯
Yeah, come fuck with me now, Louis.
來啊  你以為我窩囊嗎
Come on. You think I'm soft, huh?
來啊  我會打爆你這個黑鬼
Yeah.I'll bust one in your ass.
弗洛伊德  你再胡鬧
Floyd, you keep fucking around,
我會把槍一直插到你的屁股
I'm gonna stick that gun so far up your ass,
你每次說話都會覺得有火藥味
you gonna taste gunpowder every time you talk.
-讓我...  -該死
- Well, let me...  - Shit!
見鬼
God damn it!
路易斯  我發誓  這是意外
Louis, that was a accident. I swear.
我出汗了  手潮
I'm sweating. My hand's wet.
你沒事吧
You all right?
你不冷吧  你熱嗎
You warm? You hot?
你頭暈嗎  是不是有些眩暈
You dizzy? You light-headed?
路易斯 夥計
Louis,
我保證我從來都沒想過要傷害你
I swear I would never want to hurt you, man.
我想過殺了你  但我從來都不想傷害你
I thought about killing you,but I'd never want to hurt you.
好啦  為表我們對馬庫斯·胡克斯無盡的懷念
All right.In our continuing tribute to Marcus Hooks,
讓我們在下一首歌裡從頭回憶
we're reaching all the way back in this next song.
路  是我們的歌  夥計
Lou. That's us, man.
-聽著  -馬庫斯·胡克斯和正拳組合
- Listen.  -... Martin Hooks and The Real Deal.
1969年榜上排名第三的歌曲《我是你的玩偶》
Number 3 in 1969...  "I'm Your puppet. "
拉拉繩
Pull the string
我就向你眨眨眼
And I'll wink at you
我是你的玩偶
I'm your puppet
我會逗你笑
I'll do funny things
如果你想要
If you want me to
我是你的玩偶
I'm your puppet
來啊  路
Come on, Lou.
我得替他說句公道話  這混蛋還真會唱歌
I'll say this for him...  that motherfucker could sing.
公認的  公認的  快來  幫幫忙  和我一起
No doubt. No doubt.  Come on, help me... help me out.
-第二段  -第二段
- Second verse.  - Second?
"拉拉繩"  "親吻"
"Pull my strings. " Kiss.
...你的玩偶
...your puppet
-什麼  -你準備好了嗎
- What...  - You ready?
1  2  3
1, 2, 3.
開始
Hit it.
牽牽另一條繩
Pull another string
我就會吻你的雙唇
...ing, and I'll kiss your lips
我是你的玩偶
I'm your puppet
踏腳
Tap.
只要敲敲響指
Snap your fingers
我就做幾個後空翻
And I'll turn you some flips
我是你的玩偶
I'm your puppet
-夥計  我的胯骨太疼了  -後撤步
- Man, my hip hurt like anything.  - Drop step.
後撤步  你知道我現在做不了
Drop step?  You know I can't do that right now.
你來吧  路
Go, Lou.
很流暢  就這麼做  路易
Oh, sweet. Do it, Louie.
我是你的玩偶
I'm your puppet
-哦  是的  我就是  -再來一遍
- Oh, yes, I am  - One more time.
-該你了  弗洛伊德  -我是你的玩偶
- There you go, Floyd.  - I'm your puppet
來吧
Oh! Come on now.
知道  我跟上了
Yeah, I got it now.
跟上了
I got it.
我是你的玩偶
I'm your puppet
接下來你給我們預訂了哪裡
So where'd you book us next?
就這
This is it?
得克薩斯州  阿馬里洛市
距阿波羅演出還有3天
來啊  孩子們
Come on, children
全部湊過來
And gather around
讓你們看看
Want y'all to see
我們在下蹲
We're putting down
這事情  誰都能辦到
It's a thing everybody can do
來啊  孩子們
So come on, children
一起來搖擺
Do the boogie, too
搖擺沒什麼難
Boogie ain't nothing
只要彎彎腰
But gettin' down
搖擺沒什麼難
Boogie ain't nothing
只要彎彎腰
But gettin' down
我為你搖擺
I got to boogie for you
弗洛伊德·亨德森
Floyd Henderson
怎麼啦
What is it?
一起來搖擺
Boogie on down
路易斯·海因茲
Louis Hinds
一起來搖擺
Boogie on down
跟著樂隊
Listen to the band
我們一起搖擺
We'll make it through
讓我們  一起搖擺
All we got is the boogie, too
我為你搖擺
I got to boogie for you
寶貝  你怎麼樣  想為我搖擺嗎
Hey, you, what you got, baby? You got to boogie for me?
來吧  開始
Come on, now.
來吧  要搖擺
Come on, fiddler.
我知道你們想掌控舞台
I knew you were gonna try to take over.
看看他
Look at him.
繼續  路
Go on, Lou.
搖擺沒什麼難
Boogie ain't nothing
只要彎彎腰
But gettin' down
搖擺沒什麼難
Boogie ain't nothing
只要彎彎腰
But gettin' down
搖擺沒什麼難  只要彎彎腰
Boogie ain't nothing but getting down
搖擺沒什麼難
Boogie ain't nothing
只要彎彎腰
But getting down
我為你搖擺
I got to boogie for you
我就是想要擺
I got nothing but boogie
只想為你搖擺
Nothing but boogie for you
我就是想搖擺
I got nothing but boogie
只想為你搖擺
Nothing but boogie for you
搖擺  搖擺  搖擺  搖擺
Boogie, boogie, boogie, boogie
我為你搖擺
I got to boogie for you
有愛共享  寶貝
Share the love, baby.
你剛在台上做了招牌動作  對吧
You know you pulled the Al Green up there, right?
我沒有  路  別提那個
No, I didn't, Lou. Don't start that...
我們剛剛下台
We barely got offstage
你就屁顛屁顛的跑回去了
when you ran your ass back out there.
要不要返場觀眾說了算
Look, an encore is at the audience's discretion.
你應該等他們要求再這麼做
You're supposed to wait till they ask for it.
-你知道他們想要返場  -我不關心他們想不想
- You know they wanted it.  - I don't care what they wanted.
你的行為太不專業了
That shit was unprofessional.
夥計
Man...
噢
Say,
我記起為什麼我喜歡公路旅行啦
I'm starting to remember why I love the road so much.
就是這個
Yeah.
如果我的直覺是正確的
If my instincts serve me right,
你今晚得給自己另開個房間了
you're about to find yourself another room tonight.
你知道那些藍色小藥丸會讓你失明  對吧
You know those little blue pills make you go blind, right?
你要是持續勃起  可別喊我救命
Don't call me when you get that four-hour erection.
來吧  小寶貝
Hey, now, baby girl.
來吧  來吧
Yeah, yeah. Come on.
給我吧
Yeah, give it to me.
小藥丸給我力量吧
Those little pills, give me strength.
一點就夠了
A little strength.
今晚一定讓你爽死
I'm going to fuck your brains out.
天啊  你真重
Oh! Oh, you're heavy.
怎麼了  寶貝
what's wrong, baby?
沒什麼
Nothing.
我只是  我...
I just, uh, you know, I...
我從來沒和像你這樣的人做過
I just never been with someone like you before.
傳說都是真的  但是讓我告訴你
It's true what they say.  But let me tell you something.
弗洛伊德·亨德森很好很溫柔
Floyd Henderson gonna be nice and gentle.
你的第一個黑男人
Your first taste of dark meat
會讓你欲仙欲死  相信我
gonna be smooth and sweet, trust me.
我不是說這個
No, I didn't mean that.
我只是
It's just, uh, you know,
從來沒和像你這麼老的人做過
I've never been with someone so old.
老
Old?
你他媽也不是什麼小女生
You ain't no teen queen your damn self.
別這樣  老婆子  過來  寶貝
Come on, mama. Come here, baby.
寶貝  寶貝  聽著
Baby, baby. Look here.
讓我們用上積攢了幾十年的性經驗
Let's take our decades of sexual experience
在這個探索與狂喜之夜
and combine them for one night
盡情結合  怎麼樣
of exploration and bliss, can we do that?
我不會讓你失望的
I won't disappoint you.
好吧
All right.
這就是我所說的
That's what I'm talking about.
我要吃你的奶
I want to suck one of them titties.
真的  我有東西讓你看
Oh, yeah? Well, I got something to show you.
我全身發熱  忍不住要搞我自己
I'm so hot, I'm about to fuck myself.
使勁吻我
Bite my lip off.
哎呀
Oh. Look!
來吧  我忍不住了  寶貝
Oh, shoot, I'm leaking, girl.
今晚我得大干一場
Tonight I ain't got no control like that no more.
希望你不會介意毛太多
Now, I hope you don't mind a little hair.
寶貝  60年代我就性覺醒了
Baby, I found my sexual awakening in the '60s.
我最喜歡又硬又多毛茸茸
Nothing I like better than a big old fluffy...
見鬼  娘們兒
Damn, girl.
你的陰毛可真是茂盛
That's a whole bunch of hair you got down there.
是吧  我把它稱作自然景觀
Yeah, I call it the natural look.
你那是有什麼毛病嗎
You sick?
我知道是多了一些
I know it's big.
你得剃掉點
You need a pick.
你想讓我先刮一刮嗎
You want me to shave it?
我們沒時間也沒工具去幹那活兒
We ain't got the time or apparatus for that type of job.
好吧  忽略這個問題
Okay, disregard.
看看誰來吃飯了
Look who's coming to dinner.
正是時候  對吧
Right on time, ain't it?
我絕對是個硬漢
They call me Mr. Tibbs.
你知道接下來我要做什麼嗎
You know what I'm gonna do for you?
你準備做什麼
What you fixing to do?
你曾有過絲絨滑過的感覺嗎
You ever had a velveteen rub?
絲絨滑過
A velveteen rub.
別用奶酪  可以嗎
Ain't... Ain't no cheese involved, is there?
因為我乳糖過敏
Because I'm lactose intolerant.
來吧
Oh, yeah.
你想掐死我的小弟弟嗎
You're choking my chicken!
昨晚一定和那個大胸女
That's quite a show you got going
上演了一場好戲吧  猛男
under the big top there, Sparky.
搞的我不得不在半夜
I had to take another one of them damn pills
又吃了一次那該死的藥
in the middle of the night, man.
那個女人總是難以滿足  我簡直精疲力盡
This woman insatiable, man. I'm shooting dust.
弗洛伊德
Oh, Floyd.
寶貝  我在這
I'm right here, baby.
你準備好了再幹一場了嗎
You ready for some more?
是的  來吧
Yeah, come here.
過來
Come here.
還有什麼話說  小子
Think about that, boy.
我的小種馬在這裡哪
There's my stallion.
-我想要你  -你想要我嗎
- I missed you. - Oh, you missed me?
你得讓這裡透透氣
Mmm. You need a little air on this thing.
你這個壞孩子
Oh, you bad boy.
該死的
God damn.
你喜歡這樣嗎
You like that, huh?
我是你的小貓咪
I'm your little kitty cat.
是純真嗎
Chastity?
媽媽
Mama?
你這個小蕩婦
You little whore.
你自己不也一樣
You're one to talk.
你跟他搞得時候也把假牙拿出來了嗎
Oh, did you take out your teeth for him?
注意點和你媽說話的方式
You watch how you talk to your mama.
拜託  你沒資格教育我
Please, you can't talk to me like that.
你又不是我老子
You're not my daddy.
說的好  那麼誰是你老子
That's right, who's your daddy?
-你是我老子  -你的大JJ老子
- You're my daddy. - Your big daddy.
洛莎莉  你在房間裡嗎
Rosalee, are you in there?
事實上  我老子在門口
Actually, that's my daddy.
老媽  你想什麼呢
What are you thinking, Mama?
你毀了這一切
You ruined everything.
-我恨你  -你這個乳臭未乾小騷貨
- I hate you.  - You little brat.
你這個骯髒的...好吧  我愛你
You're a dirty...All right, I love you.
要常給我打電話
Call me a lot of times.
老媽  你哪根筋不對
Mama, what is wrong with you?
我再重申一遍  你是個蕩婦
I renounce you. You're a whore.
我是蕩婦
I'm a whore?
你和那個黑鬼讓我們全家蒙羞
You just shamed the whole family, you and the black man.
蕩婦
Whoa!
真是太有趣了
Whoo! That was fun.
快來  牽起我的手
So come, take me by the hand
一同離開這片煩惱之地
We'll leave this troubled land
我知道我們可以
I know we can
我會下地獄的  夥計
I'll be damned, man.
那倆婊子偷了我們的錢  夥計
Them broads stole our money, man.
但那是她們應得的
but they earned it.
是我  夥計  弗洛伊德·亨德森
Yeah, man. It's Floyd Henderson, man.
我們出了點情況
We got a situation.
怎麼了
What's the problem?
我的前搭檔
Well, my ex-partner,
就是那個墮落鬼
the degenerate that he is, man,
招了幾個野妓女  把我們洗劫一空
got some trailer trash hos, man, rip us off.
天啊  太糟糕了
Oh, wow, I'm sorry to hear that.
有什麼我能幫忙的嗎
Is there anything I can do?
是的  你能幫我們  我們需要錢
Yeah, there's something you can do. We need money.
如果沒錢
If we don't get no money,
我們就去不了阿波羅
we ain't gonna make it to the Apollo.
我不清楚這麼做的程序是什麼
I'm not sure what the procedure for that would be.
我的意思是說要經過層層批准
I mean, there's just a lot of red tape here.
你知道的
You know, uh...
我得問過再和你聯繫
I'm going to have to get back to you.
-快去問  然後馬上和我聯繫  -亨德森先生
- You do that. Get back with me now. - Mr. Henderson...
據我所知
We ain't gonna get very far on ten gallons of gas,
10加侖的汽油可支走不了多遠
I can tell you that.
我知道哪能搞到錢
I know where we can get some money.
我知道怎麼樣搞到錢
I know how to get some money.
塔爾薩  100公里
這不是愛嗎  這不是愛嗎
Ain't no love, ain't no love
正如你給我的愛
Like my baby's love
讓我不再孤獨
Ain't no lonely days
Ain't no lonely
見鬼  這到底是什麼...
Ooh, shit. What the hell is...
因為我找到一個女孩...
'Cause I ain't never, never found me a girl
該死  不  你不能這麼幹
Oh, hell, no. You didn't.
不  我能
Yes, I did.
這般愛我
To love me like
喂  喂  你腦子出問題了
Hey, hey, you're...  What is wrong with you?
別那樣抓我衣服
Don't be grabbing on me like that now.
如果你敢按門鈴
I will knock your ass out before
我就揍扁你
I let you go ring that doorbell.
來吧  老兄  打我啊  來啊
Come on, get up on me, man. Come on.
你真想找揍嗎
You really want this? Huh?
來吧  該死的
Come on... Oh! God damn.
-夥計  算了  -怎麼了
- Oh, man. Come on...  - What?
你這是怎麼了  怎麼了
What's wrong, what?
我胸口疼  夥計
I got a pain in my chest, man.
夠了  夥計  別耍我了
Come on, man. Stop fucking with me.
我看起來像是在耍你嗎
Look like I'm fucking with you, man?
拜託  夥計  幫我個忙
Come on, man, do me a favor.
把我的心臟病藥從包裡拿出來
Get my heart medicine out of my bag.
-你有心臟病藥  -快點  瞧我這副樣子
- You got some heart med...  - Oh! Come on, look.
快點  夥計  快點
Come on, man. Hurry up, man.
堅持住  老兄
Hold on, man!
該死  你這的藥
God damn, you got enough stuff in here
足夠開個藥店了
to start a drug store!
這瓶子上寫的是什麼
What it say on the bottle?
傻瓜  混蛋
Sucker, motherfucker.
我要干掉你
I'm gonna get your ass for this.
願意奉陪
I'll leave the light on for you.
什麼事  哥們兒
What up, dawg?
我們是  奧黛特的朋友
We're friends of, uh, Odetta's.
-奧黛塔  -對  她在嗎
- Odetta?  - Yeah, is she in?
她不在  夥計
No, she ain't here, man.
她什麼時候回來
Is she coming back?
說真的  估計她不會回來了
Seriously doubt it.
除非我們準備被殭屍攻擊什麼的
Not unless we fitting to have a zombie attack or some shit.
怎麼啦  傅滿楚
What's up, Fu Manchu?
-克里奧  -什麼事
- Cleo!  - Yeah?
給我出來
Get your ass out here!
有倆黑鬼找你媽
Two old niggers looking for your mama.
進來吧 你們把熱氣都放出去了
Come on in, man. You're letting the heat out.
媽媽
Mama?
外面很冷
Cold outside.
你們關節炎會發作的
Your arthritis gonna kick up.
誰啊
Who's that?
不知道
I don't know.
你們是
Yeah?
你好  小姐
Uh, how you doing, ma'am?
我是弗洛伊德·亨德森  這位是...
My name is Floyd Henderson. This is my...
我認識你們
I know who you are.
估計你們沒聽說葬禮的事吧
Guess you didn't hear about the funeral.
葬禮  奧黛特
Funeral? Odetta...
她什麼時候過世的
When did she pass?
聖誕節後她就病了
Well, she got sick right after Christmas.
之後  病情急劇惡化
After that, it went pretty fast.
什麼風把你們吹來了
So why'd you come to see her?
她欠你們錢還是怎麼著
What, she owe you money or something?
-沒有  -我們正好在附近
- Oh, no.  - We just in the neighborhood.
克里奧  臘腸放哪裡了
Cleo, I can't find the bologna!
我馬上過去
I'll be there in a minute!
快點
Hurry up!
我媽在世的話會知道你們來過
Well, if my mama wasn't dead, I'd tell her you stopped by.
克里奧
Cleo!
-稍等一下  -克  裡  奧
- Just hold on a second. - C-L-E-O!
-你到底要什麼啊  -抱歉...
- What the hell you want? - I'm sorry...
都告訴你了來這是個餿主意
I told you this was a bad idea to come here.
拜託  夥計  別這麼想
Come on, man. Don't go there.
我們走吧  好吧
Let's just go, okay?
你猜她多大了
How old you think she is?
27  28
27, 28?
我不知道  我也不在乎她多大了  走吧
I don't know how old she is, and I don't care. Let's go.
別緊張  我來看看
Chillax, let me see something.
你在幹嗎
What are you doing?
弗洛伊德  你到底找什麼呢
Floyd, what the hell are you looking for?
該死
Damn it.
我只是確認一下自己的懷疑
I'm just confirming a suspicion.
就是要做這個
That's all I'm doing.
1981年9月14日  搞定
September 14, 1981. Bingo.
真的就假不了  對吧
It kind of works itself out, don't it?
快放回去
Put it back.
聽著
Listen.
夥計  奧黛特在1980年
Odetta left me, man,
感恩節那天離開我
Thanksgiving Day, man, 1980.
-所以呢  -自己動腦子算算  混蛋
- So? - So you do the math, motherfucker.
算什麼  黑鬼  拜託
Do the math? Nigga, please...
你聽到沒
Oh, shit. You hear that?
聽到什麼
Hear what?
聽  那邊傳來的低音和聲
Listen, that bass line, right there.
真他媽見鬼
Son of a bitch.
萊斯特是我  弄臣也是我
Oh, my name is Lester, the Court Jester
黑鬼們說唱讓人作嘔
All you other rap niggas done messed up
我來教你們做小丑
I take you to school a semester
讓法院把你們帶走
Take you to court and sequester
法官和陪審都是我
I'm judge and the jury
東家小李  抓狂揮老拳
Bruce Lee, Fists of Fury.
我是萊斯特  你還想抽我
You want to whip me, the L-E-S-T-E-R
抓住妞的腰
Grab my girl by the waist
抽了妞的臉
Slap my girl in the face
老媽一死  我就佔她屋
When my mama died, I moved inside her crib
萊斯  萊斯
Hey, hey. Les, Les.
夥計  你們在這兒幹嘛
Hey, man, what you doing in here?
我們在做音樂
We're here trying to make some music.
這就是你們做的音樂
That what y'all doing?
我怎麼看不出來
I don't see no musicians.
聽著  你知道是誰唱的低音和聲
Listen, you know who played the base line
就你剛才唱的那段所謂歌詞時用的
on that stuff you got running under those so-called lyrics?
正是此人
My man, right there.
說得沒錯
Yeah, right, man.
他也不是什麼音樂人
He ain't no damn instrumentator.
大萊  看這個  夥計  是他們
Hey, yo, Big L, check it out, man. It's them, man.
他們說的沒錯
They ain't bullshitting.
我來看看
Let me see this here.
正拳組合
The Real Deal, huh?
要是就說你們是胡扯呢
Hey, I mean, so what if we jacked your shit, man? Huh?
好藝術家借鑑別人
Good artists borrow,
偉大藝術家剽竊別人  夥計
great artists steal, man.
-知道誰說的嗎  -派卜羅·畢加索
- You know who said that? - Pablo Picasso.
但文學家認為出自T·S·艾略特
But literary scholars sometimes like to attribute it to T.S. Eliot.
不  沒艾略特小姐什麼事  夥計
Hell, no. It wasn't no damn Missy Elliot, man.
出自貝貝組合
No, man, it was Bay Bay and them.
貝貝  沒錯
Bay Bay, yup.
這就是貝貝  毫無疑問  貝貝組合
That was Bay Bay, for sure, hey, Bay Bay.
聽著
Look, man.
知道嗎  對不起
You know what? I'm sorry.
未經許可我不該用你們的音樂合成新曲
I shouldn't have sampled your music without permission.
我們何不一起做首歌
Why don't we all do a song together?
歌名就叫"去你媽的低音和聲"
A song called "Fuck You and Your Bass Line. "
這就是我的感受
That's what I feel about it.
就這麼認為你們那該死的低音和唱
Here what I think about your damn bassline.
亨德森和海因茲
Henderson and Hinds!
拿走這堆破爛
Take that shit with you.
黃臉蛋的混帳
Gold-faced motherfucker.
我就是一流氓  咋地
I made that shit gangster, that's what I did.
我來教教你  夥計
Let me tell you something, man, you...
別吵了
Hey! Stop it!
Stop it!
這可是我家  聽到了
Hey! This is my house. You hear me?
我不想你們這麼瘋折騰
I don't need this shit right now.
在哥們面前你說我瘋折騰
You gonna talk to me crazy in front of my boys?
你還說什麼啊  給我閉嘴
Why you still talking? Shut the fuck up!
佩佩和吱吱
Pay-Pay and Zig-Zig,
我們走  夥計
let's dip, man.
再見  老黑鬼
Bye, old niggers.
好好用我的設備
Feel free to utilize my facilities while you're here
再造一次輝煌
to make yourself another hit.
艾克打敗蒂娜後你們就沒有紅過
I know you ain't had a hit since Ike hit Tina.
給我滾出去
Get out of here.
從烤架上
Get the fuck
他媽的滾開
Out my grill
趁你還活著
'Fore you get killed
萊斯特是我  弄臣也是我
My name is Lester the Court Jester.
真他媽是個無恥的混蛋
What a disrespectful son of a bitch.
-別再說了  -別說了
- Just lay off. - Just lay off?
我知道你媽想讓你學好
I know your mama taught you better.
奧黛特會讓他屁滾尿流
Odetta would've whooped his damn ass.
你他媽怎麼知道我媽會怎麼做
The fuck you know about what my mama would've done.
她得癌症要死的時候你在這裡
Were you here when she was dying of that cancer?
不在吧  但萊斯特在  你知道個屁
I don't think so. I think Lester was. The hell you know.
說的對  我屁事不知
You're right. I don't know nothing.
對  他一無所知
That's right, he don't know shit.
說得沒錯
No, he don't.
我要去換衣服做晚飯
Now I'm going to go change and get dinner started
你們會留下吧
because you guys are staying, right?
不  我們要趕路
Oh, no. We need to hit the road.
對  小姐  我們留下
Yes, ma'am. We are staying.
那好
Okay, then.
老媽肯定期望這樣
Hell, it's what Mama would've wanted.
沒錯  是奧黛特的孩子
Oh, yeah. That's Odetta's child, all right.
客房我為你們準備了
Okay, I put some sheets on the bed
鋪上新床單
In the guest room for you guys.
多謝
Thank you.
卡拉·托馬斯的歌  對吧
That's Carla Thomas, right?
沒錯  你媽最喜歡的
Sure is. Your mother's favorite.
你們怎麼就發了一張專輯
So how come you guys only put out that one album?
當我們沒爭你媽的時候
Well, when we wasn't fighting over your mother,
唱片賣得不好
we had a problem in our record sales.
我們沒賣出去多少
Yeah, as in we didn't sell any.
對
Okay.
沒準會紅起來
Well, you'd never know it wasn't a hit,
大家都像媽媽一樣喜歡
as much as Mama played it.
都要100度啦  你還穿著皮夾克
About 100 degrees, and you got a leather jacket on.
好好享受  山姆
Appreciate it, Sam.
她說過
She said,
跟你們在一起的日子
being on the road with y'all
是她一生最快樂的時光
was some of the best times of her life.
美好時光  美好時光啊
Oh, good days. Good days.
真希望能見識一下
I wish I could've seen that.
這麼說  幹嗎不跟我們去孟斐斯
Say, why don't you come to Memphis with us?
-孟斐斯  -是啊
- Memphis? - Yeah.
-什麼  -我們有個演出
- What? - We got a gig.
弗洛伊德  弗洛伊德
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Floyd, Floyd.
人家有自己的生活
The girl got a life.
她可沒空
She ain't got time to be ripping,
跟兩個老黑鬼在路上顛簸
running up and down the road with two old niggers.
為什麼不能
Why not?
孟斐斯很好玩  我們在孟斐斯總是很開心
Memphis is fun. We always have fun in Memphis.
你會喜歡的  相信我
You'll enjoy it. Trust me.
好玩  我像是有時間玩的人嗎
Fun? Look like I got time for fun?
路易斯
Hey, Louis.
克里奧告訴我
You know, Cleo was telling me
奧黛特從沒跟她談起過她父親
that Odetta never told her nothing about her father,
名字都沒提過
not even his name.
但她提過他是個音樂家
But she did say he was a musician.
你沒跟那女孩瞎說八道吧
You ain't said nothing stupid to the girl, have you?
比如
Like what?
Oh, like, uh,
克里奧  我是你爸爸
Cleo, you know, I'm your daddy.
我還要再搞清楚狀況
Well, I'm still feeling out the situation.
那你他媽幹嗎說
What the fuck was that
你應該跟我們去孟斐斯啊
that "You ought to come to Memphis with us" shit?
那樣說  會種下禍根
Now that, right there, that's a recipe for disaster.
路易斯  路易斯  我知道你肯定很難過
Louis, Louis, I know this ain't easy for you.
但是我從沒想過我有孩子
But I never thought I'd have a child.
現在我也開始生生不息了
Now I'm part of this big old circle called life.
弗洛伊德·亨德森也許真有子孫後代
A piece of Floyd Henderson, man, might be here to live on,
也許會永傳萬代
and maybe forever.
再不閉嘴睡覺
If you don't shut up and go to sleep,
混蛋弗洛伊德·亨德森
A big piece of Floyd Henderson ass
可能明天就醒不了了
Might not wake up in the morning.
路易斯  路易斯
Oh, Louis, Louis.
我很佩服你
I respect the fact that you want
能用怒火掩蓋痛苦
to cloak your pain with your anger.
晚安
Good night.
這他媽是什麼
Oh, hey! What the fuck is that?
怎麼了
What's wrong?
你又吃了那壯陽藥了
You been taking them dick pills again?
是降低膽固醇的藥  是吃了
I though it was my cholesterol meds, I swear I did.
你也不能沉迷於那玩意啊
You can't be spooning with a motherfucker with that!
你什麼毛病啊
What's wrong with you?
-我  -下作的混蛋
- Uh, I... - Nasty son of a bitch!
給我點蓋的  我去地上睡
Give me some covers. I'm gonna sleep on the floor.
混蛋
Shit.
去吧  地上睡吧
Go on, then. Sleep on the floor.
誰也不喜歡你  路易斯
Nobody wants you, Louis.
我也不喜歡娘娘腔
I don't like boy pussy no way.
疼死你的背
I hope your back hurt like a motherfucker.
起碼背疼比被戳屁眼好
Better my back than my asshole.
噁心  掄死你個狗娘養的
Nasty... I'll beat your motherfucking...
我在監獄呆那麼多年
All them years I spent in prison,
沒人敢對我這樣
ain't nobody roll up on me like that.
我正想問你
I was going to ask you about that.
你真該慚愧得要死
You ought to be ashamed of your goddamn self,
噁心的混蛋
nasty son of a bitch.
好似我從未有
Like I never had
當我傷心時
When I'm feeling bad
快點來給我安慰
Come on and comfort me
哦  寶貝  你知道路
Oh, baby, you know the way
我告訴過你  該如何愛我
I showed you how to love me right
今夜來安慰我
So comfort me tonight
快點來給我安慰  寶貝
Come on and comfort me, honey
你知道路  寶貝
You know the way, baby
因為我指給你看過
'Cause I showed you right
我需要  我需要
I want it, I want it
為何不來
Why don't you
給我安慰
Comfort me?
弗洛伊德
Floyd!
亨德森先生  亨德森先生
Mr. Henderson. Mr. Henderson?
不  我是路易斯
No, this is Louis.
海因茲先生
Mr. Hinds.
我是FC管理部的菲利浦·紐曼
It's Phillip Newman of FC Management.
你好嗎  夥計  我是你的超級歌迷
How are you, man? I'm a huge fan.
那又怎樣
So?
所以
So...
我想我已經解決了你們現金問題  夥計
I think I've solved your cash flow problems, my man.
我從父母的賬戶
I've withdrawn $10,000
取了1萬美元
from my old parents' savings account
幫你們渡過難關
to tide you over until things get sorted out.
你剛才說你是誰
Who'd you say you was again?
菲利普
Phillip.
當你關在裡面的時候
I wrote you letters when the man had you
我給你寫信了  知道嗎
locked down in the pen, you know?
我知道你是無辜的  那樣是不公平的
I know you're innocent. Shit ain't right.
好啦  菲利普  這樣
Okay, Phillip, um, look here.
我們要去孟斐斯
We're on our way to Memphis.
你5點到皮博迪酒店噴泉
Um, why don't you meet us
和我們會合
at, um, the fountain at Peabody Hotel, 5 clock.
孟斐斯  好的
Memphis. All right!
我比餓狼還餓
I'm hungrier than a mo...
你在這啊  姑娘  決定了嗎
There you are, girl. You make up your mind?
跟不跟我們去孟斐斯
You want to go to Memphis with us, or not?
怎麼決定的
What you gonna do?
怎麼回事
What happened?
沒事  沒事
Nothing. Nothing happened.
沒事
Nothing happened.
不要
No.
讓他去吧
Let him get his whupping.
你幹嗎打她
Why you hit her?
你能怎麼著
The hell you gonna do about it, man?
我可是拿著槍的  夥計
I'm the nigger with the gun, man.
見鬼
Oh, shit.
過來
Come on.
你個白化病痞子  抬起屁股跟我走
Get your albino Ike Turner ass up, uh-huh.
過來
Come on.
好吧  好吧  見鬼
Aah! Okay! Oh, shit! Aah!
我的頭髮  夥計
My follicles, man!
看著她說"很抱歉我打你了"
Look her in the eye and say "I'm sorry I hit you,
我再也不會打你了
and I'm never gonna put my hands on you again. "
-我的錯  寶貝  我不該   -照我剛才的說
- My bad, baby. I ain't... - Say what I told you to say!
很抱歉我打你了  我再也不會打你了
I'm sorry I hit you. I ain't never gonna do it again.
現在  說抱歉用我的低音和聲混音
Now, say you're sorry for sampling my bass line
抱歉踩壞了我搭檔的唱片
and for stomping on my partner's record.
抱歉用你的低音和聲混音
I'm sorry for sampling your bass line
-抱歉踩壞了你們正拳組合的唱片  -好了
- and stomping on your Real Deal record. - Okay.
現在我們要上路  需要點油費
Now, we taking a road trip, and we need some gas money.
我沒錢  夥計
I ain't got no money, man!
能幫我們不  我看到你賣那些東西了
Can you help us? I saw you out there selling that shit.
那是香菸  不是毒品  夥計  我沒有拿到...
It's weed, it ain't crack man! I ain't got...
-交出錢來  -好吧  好吧
- Give me the money! - Okay, okay.
錢在我短褲
There's money in my shorts...
沒人會伸手到你短褲裡  自己掏出來
Ain't nobody reaching in your drawers, get it out!
好的  好的
Okay, okay.
我繞在雞雞上了  夥計
I got to reach around my meat, man.
-給  -拿著
- Here. - Take it.
拿著
Take it.
天  我頭髮好疼
Oh, damn. My hair hurts.
拿著  夥計
Take it, man! Aah!
你要弄斷我的胳膊了
Ow! You're breaking my arm!
安靜
Oh, hush.
這只是小小的中國擒拿手
That's just a little Chinese submission hold.
我弄斷你的胳膊應該是這個感覺
This is what it feels like when I break your arm.
-見鬼  -弄斷他胳膊
- Shit! - Break his arm.
混蛋
Oh, bastard!
我遇到過像你一樣的混蛋  萊斯特
I know motherfuckers like you, Lester.
以前在放風場上天天能看到
Used to see them in the yard every day.
你最好祈求別坐牢
You'd better hope you don't never go inside
因為你就是當婊子的料
because you, you straight up bitch material.
那我的車怎麼辦
What about my car, man?
還問你的車
What about your car?
混蛋
Oh, shit.
我都沒穿外衣
I ain't got no clothes on.
真是混蛋
This is bullshit.
那怎樣  你趕緊穿著內褲
So what? You run around with your drawers
抬屁股滾遠點
hanging off your ass anyway.
我會殺了你的
I wasn't really gonna shoot you!
快他媽給我滾
Get the fuck out of here.
我才是拿著槍的
See, I'm the nigger with the gun now.
你最好希望我胳膊別好
You better hope my arm don't get better.
我要學空手道打你個稀巴爛
I'm gonna learn karate and kick your ass!
去你媽的
Fuck you!
你出手干涉
It was a good thing you stepped in
絕對正確  搭檔
when you did what you did, partner,
要是我逮到他
because if I'd have got a piece of him,
我要整死他  你知道的
I'd have fucked his shit up entirely, and you know that.
來吧
Come on.
跟他打我太老了
I'm too old to be tussling with the motherf...
我會一槍斃了他
I'd have shot him. I'd have popped...
我六七歲的時候  打架
I'm six, seven years older. I'd have, like, tussled...
歡迎回到靈魂之旅
Welcome back to the Soul Patrol.
我是艾薩克·赫斯
I'm Isaac Hayes.
我要大聲說出他們的名字
I want to give a shout-out
弗洛伊德·亨德森和路易斯·海因茲  正拳組合
to Floyd Henderson and Louis Hinds, The Real Deal.
他們今夜重返孟斐斯
They're back in Memphis tonight
在靈魂之屋演出
performing at the House of Soul.
1號火車開走了
Train number 1 is gone
歡迎回家  夥計們
Welcome back home, fellas.
2號火車開走了
Train number 2 is gone
3號火車也開走了
Train number 3 is been gone
我還要等你多久
How long must I wait for you
仔細看清楚
Look out with it.
這就是孟斐斯火車
It's the Memphis train
奧芬劇院
The Orpheum Theatre!
我們就在那裡演出
Our show's up in there.
我要等你多久
How long must I wait for you?
孟菲斯火車
The Memphis train
讓我再來試一次
Let me try it one more time
天啊
Oh, my God.
亨德森先生  海因茲先生
Mr. Henderson, Mr. Hinds,
讓我先
let me just start off by saying...
謝謝
Thank you.
怎麼了
What's up?
菲利浦  今晚我們要在靈魂之家演出
Phillip, tonight we're playing at the House of Soul.
一定要來啊  寶貝
Make sure you be there, baby.
一定去
Right on.
你好  歡迎來皮博迪
Hello. Welcome to the Peabody.
您需要什麼
How can I help you?
寶貝  給我3間
You can help me by giving me
你們這最好的套間
three of your best doggone suites, baby.
好的  很高興能為您服務
Well, it'll be my pleasure to assist you today.
請出示您的身份證
May I see some identification, please?
好的
Okay.
給你
Right there.
去死  路易斯
Go to hell, Louis.
亨德森先生
Mr. Henderson?
是的
It is I.
麻煩您稍等一下
Will you excuse me for just a minute, please?
好的
Okay.
-對不起  亨德森先生  -亨德森
- Ahh, I-I'm sorry, Mr. Henderson, - Henderson.
我們不能讓您住在這兒
We're unable to accommodate you.
也許我們可以為您推薦其它旅館
Perhaps we could recommend another hotel.
為什麼  夥計  我在孟菲斯
For what, man? I'm in Memphis.
我要住在皮博迪
I want to stay at the Peabody.
當然  先生  您之前住過這兒
Yes, sir, I understand you've stayed with us before,
可這就是問題所在
and apparently, that's the problem.
似乎上次您住這兒的時候
It seems that the last time you stayed here...
準確說是1978年3月12日
March 12, 1978, to be exact...
您辦了個聚會  期間  您住的房間
you hosted a party, during which the room
以及酒店的幾個其他地方
and several other areas of the hotel
遭到了大面積的破壞
sustained extensive damage.
我怎麼不記得這回事兒
I don't recollect nothing like that.
我想是斯萊和布特西
I think that's the night Sly and Bootsy
帶吞火魔術師來的那個晚上
came by with the fire-eater.
是玩蛇的那個人
Is that the one with the snake?
就是他
That's the one.
也許你可以用路易斯·海因茲的名字
Perhaps you could put those rooms
訂房看看
in the name of Louis Hinds.
沒錯
Yeah, perhaps.
路易斯·海因茲  我們試試看
Louis Hinds, we'll try that.
對不起  琳達  讓你看到這些了
I'm sorry you had to see that, Linda.
怎麼啦  我看看
What's on there? Let me see that shit.
我要看看到底怎麼了
I want to see what's on there.
我要四個房間  先生
I need four rooms, Don.
你們最好的客房
Your best available.
夥計們
Oh, hey, guys.
裁縫給了我幾件今晚的演出服
Your tailor gave me several choices for tonight.
他說他大約7點半到
He said he's going to stop by around 7:30.
那是什麼
What the fuck?
你跑去打劫花花公子商場購物了
Did you catch the sale over at the Build-A-Pimp?
你喜歡這個嗎  很棒吧
You like that? It's fly, huh?
這樣穿很時髦
It's a get-down, get-down. It's live. It's funky.
我想應該找幾個保姆
And I think I'm going to get some poonanny.
說實話
To be honest with you,
自從電視開播《老友記》  我就沒泡過妞
I haven't been laid since Friends was on television.
今晚我要好好享受
So this is my night.
你確定他不是你的孩子嗎
You sure that ain't one of your children?
今晚你會唱得很棒的
You gonna sing real nice tonight.
女歌手是誰
Who's the girl singer?
噢  天  看啊  夥計
Oh, my goodness! Look at here! Oh, man.
你好  路易斯  很高興見到你
Hello, Louis. Good to see you.
你好嗎  夥計
You good, man?
你看起來不錯
Hey, good-looking.
克勞德特  你好嗎  小妞兒
Claudette. How you doing, girl?
我知道你不會還在對
I know you still ain't upset
在巴爾的摩所發生的事難過
about what happened in Baltimore that...
你犯什麼毛病  娘們兒
Oh! What's wrong with you, woman?
直接下地獄去吧  弗洛伊德·亨德森
You going straight to hell, Floyd Henderson.
你笑什麼
What you laughing at?
-也想來一下嗎  -不
- You want some, too? - No.
去你媽的
Fuck you.
去你媽的  去你媽的
Fuck you, fuck you
這下我們沒有女歌手了
Now we have no girl singer.
我們找人代替不就行了
We just got to find a replacement, that's all.
時間不夠了
It's too late.
克里奧
Cleo.
你會唱我們所有的歌  對吧
You know all our songs, right?
別介意我直說  夥計
Ho ho ho. No offense, man,
我不和不入流的票友一起演出
but I'm not playing with no rank amateur.
別這樣  沃夫曼  她不是不入流的票友
Come on, Wolfman, this ain't no rank amateur, man.
夥計  她是奧黛特·惠特菲爾德的女兒
This Odetta Whitfield's daughter, man.
還沒出名而以
Ain't got to recognize.
真是的  那我們開始吧  寶貝
Shit. Let's roll, then, baby.
她會唱歌吧
She can sing, can't she?
我們開始
Here we go.
如果音樂讓你起舞
If music makes you move
你就盡情享受
You can really groove
享受
Groove on
如果你真的想熱戀
If you feel like you want to make love
就在滿天繁星下
under the stars above
熱戀
Love on
如果你真的有話要說
If there's something that you wanna say
卻又找不到出路
And talking is the hard way
說唱
Rap on
因為無論是什麼  只要你想做
'Cause whatever you want to do
你就應該勇往直前
You got to do your thing
如果你真的想吶喊
If you feel like you want to scream
如果這是你怒氣在釋放
If that's your way you let off steam
吶喊
Scream on
如果你真的想歌唱
If you feel like you want to sing
因為唱歌就是你所想
'Cause singing is your thing
歌唱
Sing on
如果你想整夜都熱戀
If you want to make love all night
因為你感覺很棒
'Cause you feel it's right
-很棒  -噢  沒錯
- Right on  - Oh, yeah, girl.
很棒
Right on
因為無論是什麼  只要你想做
'Cause whatever you want to do
你就應該勇往直前
You got to do your thing
我是這樂隊的  是的  這是一支夢幻般的樂隊
I'm with the band. Yeah, it's a dream.
是的  就是一支夢幻般的樂隊
Yeah, it's a... it's a total dream.
我彈哈姆菲卡
I play the harmuffica.
我幫你看著位子
I'll save you a seat.
因為無論是什麼  只要你想做
'Cause whatever you want to do
太棒啦  寶貝兒
Yeah, baby, oh
你就應該勇往直前
You got to do your thing
今晚是我一生中最瘋狂的一晚
This is the most insane night of my life.
艾薩克想讓我去他的工作室
You know Isaac wants to put me in his studio?
他說他有一首歌非常適合我唱
He says he's got a song that'd be perfect for me.
噢  真的嗎
Oh, he does, does he?
別這樣  不是你想的那樣
Uh... Come on, now. It ain't like that.
總會是那樣的
Oh, it's always like that,
就像電影裡演的
like movies.
好吧  我會小心點的
Well, I'll be careful.
只是擔心你而已  沒別的
Just trying to look out for you, that's all.
謝謝你們為我做的一切
Thanks, guys, for everything.
你就應該勇往直前
You got to do your thing, hey
再見
See you later.
如果你真的想熱戀
If you feel like making love
因為這是你所想
'Cause that's your thing
很棒
Right on
夥計  這不是正拳組合的車嗎
Man, ain't that the Real Deal car?
那當然  朋友  你是歌迷
Sure is, homie. You a fan?
是的  我是超級歌迷
Hell, yeah. I'm a big fan.
你知道他們在哪兒嗎
You know where they at?
因為我要找他們訴訴苦
'Cause I need to holler at 'em.
說實話我是他們的經紀人
Actually, I'm their manager.
真的  他們的經紀人
Really? Their manager?
等一下
Hold on a minute.
弗洛伊德
Oh, hi, Floyd.
進來吧  看看這地方
Come on in. Check this place out.
我會習慣上這裡的
I could get used to this.
我肯定你會的
I'll bet you could.
喝一杯吧
Let me get you a drink.
好的  給我來一杯
Yeah, I'll take one.
等等  先別去倒酒
But hold on, before you do that,
有件事想和你說
there's something I want to say to you.
是讓你吃驚的事情
It's been a blast connecting with you.
我想你該知道這件事
I want you to know that.
你真好
That's sweet of you.
如果你有什麼需要
And if you need anything,
比如錢什麼的
like money or something like that,
直接告訴我
don't you hesitate to call me now.
不是因為錢能彌補
Not that money gonna make up for
我們沒有在一起的日子
the lost time between us
或是別的什麼
or nothing like that.
逝去的日子
Lost time?
你要理解
You have to understand,
奧黛特從來沒有告訴過我有關你的事
Odetta never told me nothing about you.
如果我一開始就知道有你
Had I known about you from the beginning,
我會在你身邊的
I'd have been here from the start.
-弗洛伊德  -她從沒向我提過你的事
- Floyd... - She never said nothing to me about you.
弗洛伊德  你不是我父親
You're not my father, Floyd.
你沒在聽我說
You're not listening.
你的事  什麼  你說什麼
See, the thing you... what's that? Say what?
你不是我父親
You're not my father.
我不是
I- I'm not?
你不是
No.
你怎麼知道
How do you know?
因為我父親知道我
Because he knows who I am
或者他曾經知道我
Or he did.
我是說  就我所知
I mean, for all I know,
他可能已經死了
he could be dead.
每過一段時間   他會寄錢給我
I get a little money from him every once in a while.
是他許多年前設立的保密委託
It's a blind trust he set up years ago.
錢從他的音樂版稅來
Something to do with his music royalties.
音樂版稅
Music royalties?
你上了我老婆  你這混賬東西
You knocked up my wife, motherfucker.
你先從我這偷走她的
Ooh. You stole her from me first.
你發什麼瘋
What is wrong with you?
你失去了你的...
You lost your...
你沒和克里奧說吧
You didn't tell Cleo, did you?
沒有  我沒告訴她
No, I didn't tell her.
雖然我應該告訴她
I should've told her, though.
你一定笑翻了吧
I'll bet you laughing your ass off, wasn't you?
四處散佈說我才是那女孩的父親
Going around, talking about I'm the girl's daddy
還有生生不息之類的廢話
and big round circle of life, all that bullshit.
笑吧  笑吧  混賬東西
Giggle, giggle, motherfucker.
就那麼一點點
Well, just a little bit.
弗洛伊德
Floyd...
聽著  弗洛伊德
Look, Floyd...
弗洛伊德  放下  放下
Floyd, put it down. Put it down!
兄弟  別這樣
Dawg, come on!
住手  不然你會受傷的
You need to quit before you get hurt.
聽著  弗洛伊德
Look, Floyd,
我不是故意的  行了吧
I didn't mean for it to happen, all right?
你知道她是什麼人
You know how she was.
拉我一把
Come here.
好了  夥計  別再犯傻了
Come on, man. Stop acting a fool.
你沒事吧
You all right?
混蛋  別再犯傻了
Aw, shit. Quit acting a fool!
去你大爺的
Fucking dad!
你他媽的又什麼不對了
What the fuck is wrong with you?
暫停
Time out.
夥計  嘗到我那一拳的利害了吧
Still got a little pop in your punch there, partner.
嘗嘗這一拳  混賬
Pop this, motherfucker!
混蛋
Shit. Ugh.
你這個混賬東西居然打我的蛋蛋
You dirty motherfucker, hitting me in the nuts.
混蛋
Ooh! Shit.
路易斯  不可能一直是你扁我
Louis, you just can't keep whooping on my ass.
我也是他媽的男子漢  寶貝
I'm a motherfucking man, baby.
我也是他媽的男子漢
I'm a motherfucking man.
路易斯  你怎麼能不去看你女兒呢
Louis, how come you won't see your own daughter?
混蛋  我想去看她
Oh, motherfucker, I wanted to see her,
但是
but, you know...
是時機  過一段時間以後
It's time... After a while,
就變得  就變得難以承受
you know, it's just... it's just too much.
奧黛特為什麼不告訴她
Why didn't O tell her?
夥計  奧黛特為什麼不告訴她
Why didn't Odetta tell her, man?
讓她說什麼
What was she going to tell her, huh?
說她父親是個又酗酒又吸毒的人渣
That her daddy was a alcoholic dopehead convict
說她父親一事無成
that fucked up everything he touched, hmm?
不行  不行
No, no.
沒有我她過得更好
She was better off without me.
混蛋
Oh, shit.
不管怎樣  一切都太晚了
Anyhow, it's too late now.
遇見她是個錯誤
It was a mistake getting to know her.
-路  -怎麼啦
- Lou... - What?
你怎麼了  發病了
What is wrong with you? You having a seizure?
怎麼啦  怎麼啦
What? What?
克里奧
Oh. Cleo.
-克里奧  等等  -讓一讓
- Cleo, wait. Ow! - Excuse me.
該死的  等等
God damn it. Wait!
聽我說
Let me talk to... ow!
走開  該死的
Move, God damn it!
回來  克里奧
Come here, Cleo!
報警
Call the police.
你  白小子
Hey, yo, white boy.
你真的在音樂圈工作
You really in the music business?
幹嗎  你有帶子需要混音
Why, do you have a mix tape?
你他媽的給我閉嘴  白小子
Shut the fuck up, white boy!
還有別再流那麼多汗
And stop sweating so goddamn much.
你聞起來像臘肉
You smell like bacon.
而我吃素
And I'm a Muslim on Saturdays.
你哪根筋不對
Fucking wrong with you, huh?
明明是白人卻留非洲人的頭髮
How you white and got a afro?
一點兒也不帥
That ain't cool.
該死的  我頭疼
Damn, my head hurt!
克里奧出來了  克里奧出來了
Hey, there go Cleo. There go Cleo.
出租車
Taxi.
我的寶貝兒就在那裡
There go my baby, right there.
她去哪兒
Where she going?
去哪兒  寶貝
Where to, honey?
克里奧
Cleo!
該死
Oh, hell, yeah.
那個像史奴比的老混蛋也出來了
There go that old Snoop Dogg-looking motherfucker.
正拳樂隊
Real Deal,
他們就要完蛋了
hey fitting to be real dead!
我來了  老傢伙
I'm coming for you, old man!
萊斯  給這些老混蛋點厲害瞧瞧  夥計
Hey, yo, Les, let them old motherfuckers have it, man.
-我去了  -去吧  黑鬼
- I'm going for it. - Go for it, nigger.
搞定這些混蛋
Get them motherfuckers.
停下  夥計
Come on, now.
你知道只有我才能開這輛車
You know I'm the only who drive the Mothership, man.
看萊斯特怎麼把這兩個混蛋幹掉
Watch this shit with Lester about to kill on these motherfuckers.
這是我們的生存方式  我們就這麼做
That's how we live, we do it like that.
路易斯
Louis!
我回來了
I'm back!
他有槍
Gun!
糟糕  混賬萊斯特弄砸了
Oh, shit! Motherfucking Lester got fucked up!
該死的
God damn!
我要趕緊離開這糟糕的...
I'm out of this motherfucker...
-萊斯特怎麼辦  老兄  -去他媽的萊斯特
- What about Lester, man? - Fuck Lester.
就是  去他媽的萊斯特
Yeah, fuck Lester!
你都不認識萊塞特  夥計
You don't even know Lester, man.
你幹嗎撞我  夥計
Why you run over me, man!
你們這兩個老雜種
You old dirty bastard!
老非洲
Old Jim Brown, Fred Williamson,
欺軟怕硬的混蛋
two-the-hard-way motherfuckers!
我發誓要殺了你們
I'll kill you, I swear...
混蛋
Aah! Shit!
夥計  至少讓我幹掉你一次
Let me kill you one time at least, man!
你把車子弄壞了
You done fucked up the Mothership.
我應該一刀刺進你的喉嚨
I ought to stab you in your throat.
去你媽的
Fuck you! Aah!
你聽見了嗎
You hear that?
崩了這個混蛋  路易斯
Shoot that motherfucker, Louis.
舉起手來
Get your hands up!
我舉不起來  夥計  我胳膊打著繃帶
I can't, nigger. My arm's in a brace.
放下武器  快點
Drop the weapon now! Come on!
我是第一次進這種地方
This is my first time ever being in here.
安靜點
Quiet, please.
摩菲爾監獄  距離演唱會還有一 天
這個骯髒的地方
This filthy-ass motherfucking place,
弄的我渾身發癢
man, got me itching.
看守
Yo, turnkey!
快點放我出去
Come on and let me out of this motherfucker!
你應該面對現實
You might want to wrap your mind around the fact
現實就是我們要錯過演出了
that we're gonna miss that show.
你他媽說什麼  夥計
Fuck you talking about, man?
明晚我們一定要到紐約
We gotta be in New York tomorrow night.
不包括我
Uh-uh. Not me.
我受夠了  精疲力竭
I've had enough. I'm done.
什麼  你要丟下我一個人  路易斯
What, you're walking out on me, Louis?
聽著  佛洛德  在你到我家之前
Look, Floyd, I was doing just fine
我還好好的
before you showed up at my door.
你應該感謝我
That's the thanks I get
把你從破老鼠洞裡救出來
for pulling you out of that fucking rat hole.
你本來應該坐在那兒
You was just sitting up in there,
坐在那兒等死
just sitting there waiting to die.
拜託  黑鬼
Negro, please.
你比我好不到哪去
You ain't no different from me,
你侄子把你這老年痴呆趕走
Especially since your nephew put your senile ass out to pasture
還搶了你生意
and stole your business.
混蛋  路易斯
Fuck you, Louis.
快滾回你的破老鼠洞吧
Crawl back under that damn rock you've been living.
我不需要你
I don't need you.
我自己能搞定
I'll do this shit by my damn self.
看守
Yo! Turnkey!
讓我從這個鬼地方出去
Come on and let me out of this motherfucker.
我受夠了  我要見律師
I've had enough, man. I want my lawyer.
放鬆  放鬆
Relax, relax.
你不需要律師了
You ain't gonna need no lawyer.
目擊者證實了你的說辭
Witnesses say your story checks out,
所以  先生  你可以走了
so you, sir, are good to go.
太好了
Yeah.
等等  搖滾小子
Whoa. Hold on there, Chuck Berry.
你可能需要請個律師
You're gonna need a lawyer.
你越過州界違反了假釋條款
Seems crossing state lines is in violation of his parole,
更別說持有槍支
Not to mention possession of firearms
和無照駕駛
and driving without a license.
無照
No license?
借一步說話
Step back for a minute.
希望你爛死在這兒
I hope your ass rot up in here,
你他媽的罪有應得
you criminal-bound motherfucker, you.
老子曰  "不欲以靜  天下將自定"
As Lao-Tzu says, "Let things flow forward as they may. "
那我就順其自然了  寶貝
And I'm gonna let it flow, too, baby.
我也給你點亞非後裔哲學  朋友
And I got some Blackanese philosophical shit for your ass, pal.
你能矇混  但是沒法逃脫  路
You get by, Lou, but you don't get away.
黃泥巴掉到褲襠裡  不是屎也是屎
You sit in shit, you start to smell like it,
所以自己小心別沾上
so check the crack of your ass.
還有些東西給你
Here's something else for you.
這是她的號碼
Here go her number.
給她打電話吧  老爸
Call her... Daddy.
去死吧
Fuck him, man!
我得快點離開這個鬼地方
Let's get on out of this motherfucker.
他啥也不是
He ain't worth two damn flies smashed.
這個黑鬼
Nigger.
我能打個電話嗎
Can I make a phone call?
你要丟下我一個人  路易斯
You walking out on me, Louis?
我受夠了  精疲力盡
I've had enough. I'm done.
你沒事吧  夥計
You all right, man?
是的  是的  我很好
Um, yeah, yeah. I'm all right.
你一點也不好  呼吸都困難
You're not all right. You can't hardly breathe.
你需要做胸部X光檢查
You need a chest X-ray.
我不想復出
I ain't trying to make no comeback.
我已經離開  就不想回去
I'm gone, and I want to stay gone.
你應該感謝我
That's the thanks I get
把你從破老鼠洞裡救出來
for pulling you out of that rat hole,
坐在那等死
just sitting there waiting to die...
sitting there waiting to die...
- 死  死  - 太晚了
- die, die...  - It's too late.
在座的有醫生嗎
Is there a doctor in the house?
抓緊時間
Keep it short.
我是克里奧  請留言
It's Cleo. Please leave a message.
克里奧  我是路易斯
Cleo... um, this is, uh, Louis.
路易斯·海因茲
Louis Hinds.
你父親
Your father.
這麼說有點奇怪
Wow, um, feels funny saying that.
我以前從沒這麼說過
I've, um, I've never said it before.
聽著
Listen.
我沒別的意思
I didn't mean what I said.
我只是
I was...
奧黛塔是我生命中的最愛
Odetta was the love of my life.
對我來說最糟糕的
The worst thing that ever happened to me
就是失去你們
was losing her and you.
但是你現在這麼優秀
But you turned out great.
她把你教育得很好
She did a wonderful job with you.
你媽媽是個了不起的女人
You know your mother was an amazing woman.
我只想告訴你
And I just want you to know
我非常  非常高興見到你
I'm really, really glad I met you.
我希望我
And I wish I...
好啦
All right.
你他媽的知道自己在幹什麼嗎
What the fuck do you think you're doing?
把你救出監獄
Busting your ass out of jail.
你看我像在幹什麼
What the fuck does it look like I'm doing?
後退  宅男  把鑰匙拿出來
Back up, Red. Get your keys out.
打開牢門  懂嗎
Open that cell, okay?
長官  別聽他的
Deputy, don't listen to him.
他不會開槍的  至少打不中
He will not shoot you. Not on purpose anyway.
別被他騙了  宅男
Don't let him get you fucked up, Red.
我會毫不猶豫地開槍
I'll kill you disco-dead.
打開牢門  先生
Now open that doggone cell, man.
別抖  否則我也會抖
Stop shaking. If you shake, I'm gonna start shaking.
接下來你知道怎麼做
Next thing you know, kapow!
進去
Go on in.
現在把鑰匙給他
Now hand him the keys.
快給他
Hand them to him.
-好了嗎  -弗洛伊德
- Okay?  - Floyd.
你真的要這麼做
You sure you want to do this?
是不是每件事都要跟我爭
Does everything gotta be a fucking argument with you?
該死的  快出來
God damn! Come on out of there!
關門  路  鎖上
Close the door, Lou. Lock it up.
我是人質
I'm a hostage.
如果你不他媽的閉嘴
You're gonna be a dead hostage
你就將變成死人質
if you don't shut the fuck up.
看這裡  宅男
Now look here, Red.
總的來說  我欣賞你
I like you, almost.
打電話給除了老媽以外的人  就是找死
You call anybody outside your mama, kapow.
明白嗎
Okay?
咱們走吧
Let's get out of here.
有人跟蹤嗎  夥計
Anybody following us, man?
目前沒有
Not yet.
不過我打賭馬上會有
But you can bet your ass they will be.
路  我們得棄車逃跑  夥計
Lou, we gotta dump the Mothership, man.
我們得棄車
We gotta dump it.
你能丟下你的愛車
You'd abandon the Mothership?
從法律上來說我們是逃犯
We're fugitives from the law.
我們的按逃犯的思路考慮問題
We gotta start thinking like it.
逃犯不是我們
We're not fugitives, O.J.
而是你  我是人質
You're a fugitive. I'm a hostage.
這是我的說辭  而且我會堅持
That's my story, and I'm sticking to it.
等等  等等  等等
Wait, wait, wait.
看  看  看
Hold, hold, hold, hold, hold, hold.
看那邊  夥計
Look at that right there, man.
那不是萊斯特的車嗎
Ain't that Lester's car?
混蛋
Motherfuckers.
我們餓了  夥計
We're hungry, man.
來點烤雞什麼的
Come up with some baked chicken or something.
他們又開始了
They're at it again.
該死的  萊斯特的車
Oh, shit! Lester's car!
- 聽見了嗎  - 什麼
- You hear that? - What?
那個
That.
哦  我的天啊  天啊  不
Oh, my God! Oh, God, no! Oh, God...
海因茲先生  亨德森先生
Mr. Hinds. Mr. Henderson.
看見你們太好了
It's so good to see you.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
你都不知道  裡面有多熱
Oh, it was so hot in there. You have no idea.
如果有什麼我能幫忙
If there's anything I can get you,
比如來杯拿鐵咖啡  我就是為你們服務的
like a latte, I'm here for you guys.
但是我得先去方便一下
But first I really have to pee,
所以我得先跳出去
so I'm just gonna hop on out.
請你能拉我一把
If you could give me a hand out of here.
我被關在這兒
I've been locked in there,
他們還整天開著低音喇叭
and they've had the woofers going all day.
天啊
Oh, my God.
我得去撒尿  如果你不介意
I just have to pee real bad, so if you don't mind.
看見你們太好了
It's so good to see you.
海因茲先生
Oh, Mr. Hinds...
馬庫斯·胡克斯的遺體
The body of Marcus Hooks
今天早晨抵達肯尼迪機場
arrived at Kennedy Airport earlier this morning,
並受到國王般的迎接
and in a processional befitting a king,
隨後將會送到本州的阿波羅劇院
will make its way to the Apollo Theatre,
在那裡遺體會安置得
where it will lie in state...
我正在看
I'm watching it right now.
十分妥當
...appropriately enough,
遺體放在一個鋼琴形狀的棺材裡
in a piano-shaped coffin
以便上千名悼念者
for the thousands of mourners gathered
為優秀的靈魂樂先鋒送行
to pay tribute to the beloved soul pioneer.
插播  其他相關消息
Meanwhile, in related news,
警方正在全力緝拿
authorities continue the search
弗洛伊德·亨德森和路易斯·海因茲
for Floyd Henderson and Louis Hinds,
他們於今天凌晨越獄
following a daring jailbreak early this morning.
這兩個人已經在
The two backup singers were on their way
去往紐約的路上
to New York City
打算出席晚上的悼念儀式
to perform at tonight's tribute
來紀念昔日的夥伴
honoring their one-time partner.
該死
Fucking A!
當前經濟不斷增長
Local economy is getting a big boost from...
是的  不  不  我明白
Yeah. No, no. L... I understand.
我有電話進來
Uh, that's my other line.
稍後給你回電話  我是丹尼
I'll call you back. This is Danny.
你好  愛普斯坦先生
Hello, Mr. Epstein.
菲利普·紐曼  我上週弄壞了你的訂書機
Phillip Newman. I broke your stapler last week.
-沒有搞錯吧  -在聽嗎
- Are you kidding me? - Hello?
該死的你在哪
Where the hell are you?
聽著  我打電話來是要告訴你
Listen, I called because I just wanted to let you know
一切都很好  都在我們掌控中
that everything's cool, and we're still on target.
我們
We?
你跟亨德森和海因茲在一起嗎
You're with Henderson and Hinds?
是的  先生
Yes, sir.
雖然他們總是說"混蛋"
They say "motherfucker" a lot,
但他們都是好人
but they're really good guys.
好吧  很好
All right, well, good.
你告訴他們
You can give them this message.
電視網那邊剛打電話來  他們不能出席演出
The network just called, and they're off the show.
他們不能這麼做
But they can't do that!
哦  是嗎  那可是VH1頻道
Oh, really? It's VH1.
你看過愛的滋味嗎
Have you seen Flava of Love?
他們可以為所欲為
They can pretty much do whatever they want.
還有  你被開除了
And another thing, you're fired.
混蛋  去死吧
Motherfucker! What the fuck?
他怎麼說
What'd he say?
他說我被開除了
Uh, he said I'm fired,
還有  還有  你們不能出席活動
and... and, uh, and you're off the show.
你  你說真的  夥計
Are... Are you serious, man?
對不起
I'm so sorry.
根據地圖來看
You know, uh, according to the map,
那條路通向高速公路
that road leads to the turnpike.
我們仍有時間完成
I think we've still got time to make it.
完成什麼  路易斯
Make what, Louis?
你聽見那個混蛋怎麼說的
You heard what the motherfucker said!
都結束了
It's over!
去他媽的
Fuck that.
我們說結束才是真的結束了  明白嗎
This shit ain't over till we say it's over, all right?
一切都不同了
Things have changed,
我精神上有了新的領悟
and I have achieved a state of mental clarity.
說的太好了
Ain't that a bitch?
你聽見那個混蛋的話了嗎
You hear what this motherfucker said?
夥計  從我敲你家門開始
Ever since I knocked on your door, man,
你就一直反對我
you've been beating my balls at every fucking turn.
現在突然間有領悟了
Now all of a sudden, you've got a state of clarity.
你的領悟從洛杉磯來的  路
Where was your clarity in L.A., Lou?
你不能只像訂匹薩一樣
You can't just dial that shit up
打個電話  混蛋
like you calling for a pizza, motherfucker.
一定要深入  干實事
You got to go inside, do the work.
因此  我承認
Consequently, I have a confession.
弗洛伊德  你是對的
Floyd, you were right about me.
我放棄了生命中很多事情
I have given up on a lot of things in my life.
但這次我不想放棄  行嗎
But I ain't giving up on this. All right?
來吧  夥計  我們過去幾天經歷了那麼多爛事
Come on, man, we've been through enough shit the last few days.
我們這次也可以挺過去
We can do this.
沒人敢阻止我們
And I dare anybody to try to stop us.
出發  混蛋
Let's go, motherfucker.
槍
Shotgun.
坐後面去
Get your ass in the backseat.
無法再阻止我們
Ain't no stoppin' us now
我們踏上征程
We're on the move
曾有許多事讓我們停滯
There's been so many things that's held us down
但是現在看來
But now it looks
一切都能克服
Like things are finally coming around
千萬別失望  失望
Don't you let nothing, nothing
堅定不移
Stand in your way
我要你傾聽  傾聽
I want y'all to listen, listen
我說的每個字  每個字
To every word I say, every word I say
無法再阻止我們
Ain't no stopping us now
沒有  沒有
No, no, no
我們踏上征程
We're on the move
路途奇妙
The movin' groovin'
無法再阻止我們
Ain't no stopping us now
音效和地板放射性監測器都打開  懂嗎
Full sound and switch on all the floor monitors, all right?
看那個  那個很管用很敏感
Look at that. That's nice and subtle.
我馬上做  音效測試
I'm on it, then. Sound check.
好的  謝謝
Okay. Thanks.
- 愛普斯坦先生  - 什麼事?
- Mr. Epstein. - Yeah?
你在這太好了
Hey, thank God you're here.
天  這怎麼可能
Oh, God, this isn't happening.
你在這幹什麼  我已經開除你了
What are you doing here? I thought I fired you.
我只想告訴你  我不是自己來的
I just wanted to tell you I'm not alone.
你們都瘋了
You guys are insane!
很高興見到你  小愛普
Good to see you, too, Little Ep.
這根本行不通
Yeah, this is never going to happen.
你們一旦被認出就會被逮捕
You'll be arrested the moment the cops spot you.
我們不關心那些
We don't care anything about that.
我們只想唱自己的歌
We just want to do our song.
還有一件事  你有時間嗎
Oh, one other thing. You got a few minutes?
有  我佔用了全世界的時間
Yeah, I got all the time in the world.
我正在錄製一個電視秀
I'm just producing a television show
有很多音樂明星參與
with dozens of huge musical acts
還有17分半鐘就開始直播了
that goes live in 171/2 minutes,
但是你知道  拿些咖啡來  我們談談
but you know, let's grab some coffee and have a little chit-chat.
他得這病多長時間了
Wow. How long's he got?
不知道
We don't know.
好吧
All right.
我會盡力的  好吧
I'll see what I can do. Okay?
謝謝
Thank you.
女士們  先生們  女士們  先生們
Ladies and gentlemen, ladies and gentlemen,
請各位就座
please take your seats.
儀式馬上開始
The ceremony will begin shortly.
我去開門
I'll get it.
黑人摩西
The Black Moses.
你怎麼樣  夥計
How's it going, man?
怎麼啦
Hey, what's happening?
你怎麼樣  寶貝
What's up, baby?
夥計們
Hey, fellas.
怎麼啦
Hey, what's happening?
-夥計  -我的夥計
- The man. - My man.
好啦
Okay, all right.
聽說你們來了  祝你們好運
Heard you were here. Just wanted to wish you luck.
順便說一下
Oh, by the way,
我帶了個人見你
brought somebody by to see you.
是嗎
Oh, is that right?
是的
Yeah.
好了  我們都出去吧
Okay, everybody, let's move on out of here.
快點
Come on.
好了  大家都聽見亨德森先生的話了
All right, you heard what Mr. Henderson said.
你先走  小夥子
After you, young man.
好的
Okay.
對不起我選擇了逃避
I'm sorry I ran out the way I did.
我才是逃避的人
I'm the one who ran out.
你不需要道歉
There's no need for you to apologize.
能幫你打領帶嗎
Can I help you with your tie?
當然可以
Yeah, sure.
你知道自己在做什麼嗎
You know what you're doing?
是的  我當然知道
Yeah, I know what I'm doing.
好了
Here you go.
你沒事吧
You all right?
沒事  幫我拿點水
Yeah. Just some water, please.
該死
Damn!
相機都準備好了
All cameras are on point.
剛加了兩個麥克風
We just added two mics.
愛普斯坦先生  快過來一下
Mr. Epstein! You better come quick.
快點  我是認真的
Come on, I'm serious.
快點  情況緊急
Come on! It's important!
好的  幫我照看一下這裡
All right. Take care of those.
只有15分鐘了  丹尼
15 minutes, Danny.
他突然就病發了
He just collapsed.
我覺得他肯定很痛
I think he's in a lot of pain.
張開手  張開手
Open your hand.Open your hand.
在這裡  在這裡
Right there, right there.
好了  好了
Okay, okay.
堅強點  老兄  堅持住
Be strong, brother.Hang on in there.
現在不是去醫院檢查的時候
It ain't time for you to check out now.
檢查  幹嘛
Check out? What?
行了  夥計
Come on, man.
大家都知道是怎麼回事
Everybody knows, man.
我阿姨也在用這種該死的藥  夥計
My aunt was taking the same doggone pills, man.
她一個星期  疼得又踢又叫
Took her about a week before she wasted away to nothing,
然後就越來越瘦弱直到死去
just kicking and screaming.
我不知道她得什麼病死的
I don't know what killed her ass,
但如果她是吃了這種藥  那她就有膀胱炎
but if she was taking those,she had a bladder infection.
你說什麼
Say what?
蒙古大夫  我有腎結石
Look, Doctor Dumbshit,I got a kidney stone.
雖然在尿尿的時候確實他媽的痛
Hurts like a motherfucker when I pee,
但還不至於要了我的命
but it ain't gonna kill me.
這麼說你不是要死啦
So you're not dying?
自從我們呱呱墜地  都注定了會有死的那天
From the first slap and cry,we all start to die.
但我不會死得那麼早  絕對不會
But I ain't on no accelerated program,hell, no.
真是天大的笑話
Ain't that about a bitch?
我做了這一切  把你從監獄裡劫出來
All that damn hard work,busting your ass out of jail,
但你卻還死不了
and you ain't even dying.
我多希望能看你到死的那一刻
I was kinda looking forward to seeing you go.
打擾一下  丹尼  他們兩分鐘後上台
Excuse me, Danny.They're on in two.
好的  大家都準備好了嗎  夥計們
All right. Where we at, guys?
好了  我沒事
Okay, I'm good.
猶如麥加聖地一般的阿波羅劇場
The Apollo, the mecca.
喚起了無數的美好回憶  夥計
This brings back memories, man.
我們已經在這表演過多少次了
How many times you think we've performed here?
條子
ooh, five-oh.
50場  真的嗎
50, really?
有條子
Five-oh.
快點  跑  跑
Come on. Move, move.
是他們  站住  站住
That's them! Hold it! Hold it!
所有單位注意  所有單位注意
All units report, all units report.
發現嫌疑犯
Suspects have been spotted.
所有單位  秘密拘捕他們  但記住按規章辦事
All units, apprehend them quietly and by the book.
路  你認為他們走了嗎  夥計
Hey, Lou, do you think they're gone, man?
我又不能透視  蠢貨
I don't have X-ray vision, motherfucker!
我怎麼會知道
How would I know?
聲音小點  路  該死
Lower your voice, Lou.Doggone it, man.
這裡太黑了  根本什麼都看不到
It's so dark in here you can't see shit.
等等
Hold up.
我看看能不能找到打火機
Let me see if I can reach my lighter.
別在這點打火機  夥計
Don't light no lighter up in here, man.
你想讓我們變成烤肉嗎
We'll blow up like a barbecue.
等一下
Hold on one minute.
該死的
Shit.
是他媽的馬庫斯·胡克斯
Marcus motherfucking Hooks.
這裡離林伍德大街挺遠的吧  混蛋
Long way from Linwood Street, huh,motherfucker?
去他媽的林伍德大街  還有他
Fuck Linwood Street and him.
他利用了我們兩個  這你是知道的
He used both of us, and you know it.
別這樣  老兄
Come on, man.
他只不過覺得自己是腕兒了就單飛了而已
He just thought he'd be a bigger star going solo.
他做得很對
He was right.
對個屁
No he wasn't.
他只不過不想把錢分成三份罷了
He didn't want to split the money three ways.
看看他那衰樣  傻呆呆地坐著
Just look at him, sitting there
臉上還掛著老年痴呆般的笑容
with that old shit-eating grin on his face.
你覺得自己很行  是不是  混蛋
You think you're all that, motherfucker, don't you?
我必須承認  每次只要一想到你
I have to admit, every time I think about you,
我就恨不得想把你掐死
I could just choke the shit out of you!
住手  住手
Stop it, stop it!
弗洛伊德  他沒想法  他是死人
Floyd, he ain't thinking shit. He's dead.
看啊  這不是我的表嗎
Say, ain't that my watch?
看看  你認為是我偷了那該死的
See? You thought I stole that mother...
我告訴過你這混蛋是一個盜竊狂
I told you this motherfucker was a klepto!
該死  看看那個
Shit, look at that.
真漂亮
That's nice.
也許這個也是偷的
Probably stole that, too.
這混蛋的品位向來不錯
Motherfucker always had good taste, though.
這個我留下了
I'm gonna keep this.
路易斯
Hey, Louis.
你覺得如果
You think if, you know...
如果他沒有  沒有死的話
if he wouldn't have, you know, died,
你覺得我們會再重組嗎
you think we would have got back together?
不  當然不
Oh, hell, no.
但是你知道嗎
But you know what?
我們現在在一起
We are together,
我一直在考慮我們的分配問題
and I've been thinking about our little arrangement.
我們把酬金五五分  怎麼樣
I'm gonna go ahead and break you off 50/50, all right?
路  你實在是
Wow, Lou, that's...
你實在是太夠意思了  夥計
that's real black of you, man.
但是我們其實沒有酬金
Because there ain't no money.
你說什麼
Say what?
是你自己說的
Well, you said it yourself.
這是個葬禮
It's a funeral.
沒人會花錢請你唱歌  夥計
Nobody pays you to sing, man.
那個酬金是你編出來的
You lied about the money?
-是的  -你這個混蛋
- Yeah.- You motherfucker.
但你不能說來這一趟並不值得啊
Hey, you can't say it wasn't worth it.
我是想說不值得
Well, I could say it.
但那是撒謊
But I'd be lying.
我愛你  路
I love you, Lou.
好兄弟
My nigger.
但對於這個混蛋  我忍不住
But this motherfucker,you know, I can't help it.
每一次  我都忍不住想要殺了這個混蛋
Every time,I could just kill this motherfucker!
他離開的原因就是你總是挑剔他
That's why he left, because you was always picking on him.
別跟他較勁了
Stop fucking with him.
他毀了我的幸福
He fucked with my happiness.
女士們  先生們
Ladies and gentlemen,
我是艾薩克·赫斯
I'm Isaac Hayes.
他們死到哪兒去了  丹尼
Where the fuck are they, Danny?
我親愛的朋友們  請跟我一起
My good friends, please join me
向我們的兄弟馬庫斯·胡克斯告別
in saying farewell to brother Marcus Hooks.
是路易斯和弗洛伊德
It's Louis and Floyd!
是正拳組合
It's the Real Deal!
馬庫斯·胡克斯和正拳組合
Marcus Hooks and the Real Deal,
再度聚首
back together again.
請為他們鼓掌吧
Give them a hand.
為了團聚
Reunited, y'all.
他們將再次合作
They got their shit together.
是的  讓我們拭目以待吧
Yes! Let's go!
各就各位  聽我的命令行事
Stand by.Move in on my command.
請等等  等等  等等
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
拜託了  各位警官和探長
Come on, Officer detective person.
求你們  別這樣
Please, just, you know, come on.
允許他們唱一首歌  只要一首
Let them sing one song.One little song.
不會出什麼亂子的
It's not gonna hurt anybody.
正拳組合
The Real Deal!
好吧  就一首歌
All right. One song.
但最好是好歌
But it better be good.
一首歌  一首好歌
One song. The good one.
胯骨感覺怎麼樣
How's that hip?
完全準備好了  寶貝
Locked and loaded, baby.
開始吧
Let's do this.
樂隊
Band!
我們來一首《公園漫步》
Let's take a walk in the park.
1  2  3  4
1,2,3,4!
當河水開始流淌
When the river gets to rollin'
你為其注入滿滿靈魂
And then you add a bowlful of soul in
我試著讓它盡情奔放
And then I tried to let it all go then
哦  對我來說很簡單
Oh, it's easy to me
看看  我如何駕馭節拍
You see, the way I ride the rhythm
看看  我如何只講實話
You see, the truth is all I can give 'em
而歌詞就是取自生活
And the lyrics can come from livin'
哦  耶  哦  對我來說很簡單
Oh, yeah, oh, it's easy to me
音樂就來自我的內心
Music comes out of my heart
就像漫步在公園
Something like a walking the park
就像漫步在公園一樣
It's just a walk in the park
我沒聽見  其他人在公園
And no one else in here, I heard it
我不知道  是否得償所願
I don't know what I've done to deserve it
全心投入沒有疑惑
You don't question it while you serve it
這是天賜機緣
Oh, it was given to me
賦予我你的激情
I got something you inherit
我不知道你是否為分享它而生
I don't know that you was born to share it
但是  若想成功  沒它不行
And if you shoot,be sure you wear it
哦  這是我的本性流露
Oh, it comes naturally to me
音樂就來自我的內心
Music comes out of my heart
就像漫步在公園
Something like a walk in the park
就像漫步在公園一樣
It's just a walk in the park
今也你們是否開心
Y'all having a good time out here tonight?
我就是想讓你開心
This is what I'm talking about!
你可知公園漫步  夥計
You know about that walk in the park, man?
我當然知道公園漫步
Sure I know about that walk in the park.
-真的  -讓你瞧瞧
-You do? -I'll tell you what.
-讓他們看看 -開始
- Show them. - Got to get down.
女士們  先生們
Ladies and gentlemen,
請在阿波羅劇院的舞台上
let's give a big Apollo welcome
熱烈歡迎首次在這裡表演的
to the stage for the first time,
我的女兒  克里奧·惠特菲爾德小姐
my daughter, Miss Cleo Whitfield!
全力開創一片天地
To make something out of nothin'
這是我們共同志願
That's what we all got in common
只需緊緊相擁  我就到來
So just hold on tight, I'm comin'
告訴我
Said to me
我就給你可堅持的信仰
I'll give you something you can believe in
今夜我們全身心投入
And then enjoy yourself this evenin'
你肯定不能抽身而去
And don't you dare think about leavin'
跟我一起唱
Sing along with me
音樂就來自我內心
Music comes out of my heart
就像漫步在公園
Something like a walk in the park
就像漫步在公園一樣
It's just a walk in the park
音樂就來自我內心
Music comes out of my heart
就像漫步在公園
Something like a walk in the park
就像漫步在公園一樣
It's just a walk in the park
音樂就來自我內心
Music comes out of my heart
就一首歌
One song.
因在獄中表現良好獲得減刑
正拳組合終於正式重返舞台
並且加入一名新主唱
音樂就來自我內心
Music comes out of my heart
我是他們的經紀人
I'm their manager!
就像漫步在公園
Something like a walk in the park
漫步在公園
Walk in the park
就像漫步在公園一樣
It's just a walk in the park
Just like a walk in the park
你今晚會唱得很棒
You're gonna sing real nice tonight.
快樂時光要來臨
Got that funky time
我能感受到
I can feel it
每當攝像機或者麥克風開啟之後
Any time the camera or the mic comes on,
我不會糊弄自己
I don't cheat myself.
這是我在孩提時候學到的第一條原則
That was rule number 1 I was taught as a kid.
當然我肯定也不能糊弄觀眾
And I definitely can't cheat the audience.
因此每一次做事
So I give 150%
我都會付出150%的努力
every single time that I do anything.
我的生活中也是這樣
Even the way I live my life.
我會珍惜每一次糟糕的經歷
I just cherish each doggone moment.
再說個黑人牧師的笑話吧  怎麼樣
A black preacher's something else, ain't it?
你去了教堂以後付不起房租
You can't pay your rent after you come from church.
如果你向牧師要5塊錢
And if you ask the preacher for the $5.00,
他這樣告訴你  "以神的名義操你媽"
he'll be like, "Fuck you in the name of Jesus. "
我的喜劇不是臆想出來的
My comedy is not fictitious.
我的喜劇必須得來自我的內心
My comedy has to come from my heart.
-查理·陳是個好漢  -好吧  來排練一下
- Charlie Chan was a hell of a man.- All right, let's rehearse.
上完廁所  逛過中國還沒洗手
He went through China with his shit in his hand.
五個女人靠牆站
Had five women against the wall.
我敢打賭他把她們全部都干
I betcha five dollars that he fucked them all.
他辛苦地干
He fucked them hard.
他長久地干
He fucked them long.
一直感到弟弟被抽乾
He fucked them till his shit got sore.
他去看病  大夫回答
He went to the doctor,and the doctor said,
"對不起  查理  你的弟弟已經不應答"
"Sorry, Charlie, your dick is dead. "
他說  "大夫  大夫  不是真的阿"
He said, "Doctor, Doctor,that can't be true. "
"沒錯  先生  你的蛋蛋也沒氣啦"
"Yes, sir, Charlie,your balls are too!"
我的一生都在演出
I've been performing all my life.
因此  對我來說  在觀眾面前表演
So being in front of an audience
從來都不是問題
has never been a problem for me.
該離開了
It's time to go?
那就走唄
Well, go on, then.
要給觀眾留下長久的印象
You want to leave a lasting impression on your audience.
這也是我第一次開始表演時
You know, and that's something I was taught, too,
別人教給我的
when I first started.
儘量讓觀眾記住你
Always make them remember you,
或者記住關於你的電影的一些事
or remember something about you and the film.
我要回我600美金一晚上的酒店去了
I'm going back to my $600-a-night hotel room,
來一個  一個泡泡浴什麼的
have me a nice-ass, uh,piece of pussy and shit.
是嗎
Okay?
停
Cut it.
好的  深呼吸  深呼吸
Okay, just breathe. Breathe.
我還沒進去呢
I'm not even in yet.
讓我來為你跳舞
I got to boogie for you
我為你搖擺
I got nothin' but boogie
只想為你搖擺
Nothin' but boogie for you
我只想搖擺
I got nothin' but boogie
只想為你搖擺
Nothin' but boogie for you
搖擺  搖擺
Boogie, boogie
我想對你們所有人說聲謝謝
I want to say thanks to you all
因為你們成就了我
because you all made me... yeah.
沒有你們就沒有我的電視秀或者電影
I wouldn't have no TV show or movies.
你們是為了看我才來的
You all was coming to see me,
是你們成就了我
and you all made me...
在查塔努加  路易斯安那  密西西比
Chattanooga, Louisiana, Mississippi.
謝謝你們
So thank you.
我想如果我跟其他很多人一樣
I think if I had a few free passes
度過很多的空閒時間
like a lot of people,
我就不會像現在這樣成功
I don't think I would be as successful as I have.
我經歷的最艱苦的事情
My task here on Earth
就是我必須得比常人更加地努力
is I have to work harder than the average bear.
這看起來很簡單  不是嗎
It look easy, don't it?
但實際上不是的
But it's not.
謝謝你  甜心  謝謝
Thank you, sweetheart. Thank you.
此片贈與 伯尼·麥克和阿里扎·海耶斯
兩位真正的靈魂歌手